<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>project-news on Genealogies</title>
    <link>https://monabaker.org/tags/project-news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in project-news on Genealogies</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2018 13:17:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://monabaker.org/tags/project-news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Genealogies of Knowledge Conference I (Dec. 2017): Video recordings now available</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/genealogies-of-knowledge-conference-i-dec-2017-video-recordings-now-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2018 13:17:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/genealogies-of-knowledge-conference-i-dec-2017-video-recordings-now-available/</guid>
      <description>The Genealogies of Knowledge project team is pleased to announce that video recordings of all six keynote presentations delivered during our first international conference last year in December 2017 are now available to view online. Please click on the links below to access these resources. Each speaker’s abstract and bio data can additionally be found here.  Keynote presentations &amp;nbsp;  Robert Wisnovsky,&#39;Commentaries, Translation and Philosophical Change: The Case of Greek-into-Arabic&#39; Marianne Maeckelbergh, &#39;The Practice of Unknowing: Knowledge Construction and Deconstruction in Social Movement Networks&#39; Eivind Engebretsen,&#39;Knowledge Translation (KT) as Bio-textual Crossings&#39; Edward Baring, ‘What’s Continental about Continental Philosophy?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genealogies of Knowledge Software - Developments and Enhancements</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/genealogies-of-knowledge-software-developments-and-enhancements/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 09:14:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/genealogies-of-knowledge-software-developments-and-enhancements/</guid>
      <description>The Genealogies of Knowledge project has recently announced the release of the GoK corpus browser interface for researchers wishing to work with the range of corpora developed as part of this project. This is a substantial resource which is constantly being expanded. It currently consists of the following sections:  Modern English Corpus: 17,757,212 tokens Internet English Corpus: 1,201,414 tokens Classical Greek Corpus: 2,763,315 tokens Early Latin Corpus: 866,462 tokens Medieval Arabic Corpus: 1,545,223 tokens  New Features New functionalities have also now been added to the main concordancing interface: Once you have generated a concordance, you can now delete a line by clicking on the Delete Line button in the right-hand corner of the screen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conference Programme: Genealogies of Knowledge I  2017</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/conference-programme-genealogies-knowledge-i-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 10:28:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/conference-programme-genealogies-knowledge-i-2017/</guid>
      <description>Genealogies of Knowledge I: Translating Political and Scientific Thought across Time and Space The University of Manchester 7-9 December 2017 Conference Programme The full programme of the Genealogies of Knowledge 2017 Conference can now be viewed and downloaded from the conference website, in both outline and detailed versions: http://genealogiesofknowledge.net/gok2017conference/programme/ Hosted by the research team leading the AHRC-funded Genealogies of Knowledge project at the University of Manchester, this conference will provide a forum for engaging with questions of current import in relation to the role of translation in the production and circulation of political, scientific and other key concepts in social life across time and space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Governance and Public Health in Early Nineteenth-Century Egypt</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/governance-public-health-early-nineteenth-century-egypt/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2017 09:44:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/governance-public-health-early-nineteenth-century-egypt/</guid>
      <description>Institute for the Study of Muslim Civilisations, London October 19, 2017 Part of DIALOGUES 2017: a thought-provoking series of seminars on governance in Muslim contexts The Governance Programme at the Aga Khan University&#39;s Institute for the Study of Muslim Civilisations is hosting Governance and Public Health in Early Nineteenth-Century Egypt in the fourth seminar of its 2017 Dialogues Series. Dr. Kamran Karimullah will explore the role that medical practice and medical discourse played in the historical evolution of political power and society in nineteenth-century Egypt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Democracy, Futurity, and Security in Post-Coup Cairo (Video)</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/democracy-futurity-security-post-coup-cairo-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2017 09:54:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/democracy-futurity-security-post-coup-cairo-video/</guid>
      <description>Dr. Ian Alan Paul (Al-Quds Bard College, Abu Dis, Palestine) is a transdisciplinary artist, theorist, and curator. Drawing upon his fieldwork undertaken between 2013 and 2015, this event at the University of Manchester explored the myriad forms of contestation that emerged between the diverse legacies of the January 2011 uprising and the subsequent 2013 military coup in Cairo, Egypt. The presentation features sections of the online documentary The Conditions of Possibility (2016), reflections on the production of the documentary, and analysis of the competing forms of democratic possibility and suffocating security that continue to unfold in the present.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Members of Genealogies of Knowledge Project Advisory Board</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/new-members-genealogies-knowledge-project-advisory-board/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 10:32:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/new-members-genealogies-knowledge-project-advisory-board/</guid>
      <description>We are pleased to announce that three colleagues from Manchester University have recently joined the Genealogies of Knowledge Project Advisory Board:
 Stuart Jones Stuart Jones is Professor of Intellectual History at the University of Manchester. His research interests focus on the history of political thought and of political concepts in modern Europe, on the history of universities, and on the emergent field of the history of the humanities. He is the author of The French State in Question (1993), Victorian Political Thought (2000), and Intellect and Character in Victorian England: Mark Pattison and the Invention of the Don (2007).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Henry Jones</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/henry-jones/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 12:30:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/henry-jones/</guid>
      <description>I am the second Post-Doctoral Research Associate to start work on the Genealogies of Knowledge project. Having received my BA in French Studies from the University of Sheffield, I came to Manchester in 2012 as a student enrolled on the MA in Translation and Interpreting Studies programme. During this course, I developed an interest in recent research on web-based communities of non-professional translators, as well as in socio-narrative theory as a conceptual framework for the study of translation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calls for Panel Papers: Genealogies of Knowledge I</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/call-panel-papers-genealogies-knowledge-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 12:29:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/call-panel-papers-genealogies-knowledge-i/</guid>
      <description>Genealogies of Knowledge I: Translating Political and Scientific Thought across Time and Space The University of Manchester 7-9 December 2017  &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Submission Period for Contributions to Thematic Panels Now Open The period for the submission to the conference thematic panels is now open. Paper proposals for the thematic panels should be submitted directly to panel convenors by 31 May 2017. Full details on the conference panels and their convenors can be found by clicking on the links below:  Lingua Francas of Knowledges The Magic of ‘Classical’ Languages: Script, Sound and Sense in the Translation of Sacred Concepts Translation and Health Humanities: The Role of Translated Personal Narratives in the Co-creation of Medical Knowledge Dissemination, Contestation, and Mediation of Knowledge between Asia and the West Science and Translation as Culturally Embedded Practices Data-driven conceptual history: new methods and approaches  Further Information Genealogies of Knowledge I: Translating Political and Scientific Thought across Time and Space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genealogies of Knowledge I: Translating Political and Scientific Thought across Time and Space</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/genealogies-knowledge-i-translating-political-scientific-thought-across-time-space-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 08:31:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/genealogies-knowledge-i-translating-political-scientific-thought-across-time-space-2/</guid>
      <description>Genealogies of Knowledge I: Translating Political and Scientific Thought across Time and Space The University of Manchester 7-9 December 2017 Update on Genealogies of Knowledge I Conference The selection of abstracts for the Genealogies of Knowledge I conference has now been completed. In addition to the six plenary sessions, the conference will consist of:  Approximately 40 papers to be delivered as individual presentations, as part of the general programme; Approximately 40 papers to be delivered under one of the nine thematic panels that were submitted for the organisers’ consideration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call for Panel Papers: Data-driven conceptual history: new methods and approaches</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/call-panel-papers-data-driven-conceptual-history-new-methods-approaches/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2017 08:36:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/call-panel-papers-data-driven-conceptual-history-new-methods-approaches/</guid>
      <description>Genealogies of Knowledge I Translating Political and Scientific Thought across Time and Space University of Manchester 7-9 December 2017 Data-driven conceptual history: new methods and approaches Convenors: Jaap Verheul, Pim Huijnen (Utrecht University) Call for Panel Papers (Adobe PDF) This panel aims to bring together scholars to present the state-of-the-art in digital conceptual history and to discuss epistemological and methodological questions related to computational approaches to conceptual change. The digitisation of historical material and the implementation of new computational tools have spurred the study of semantic and conceptual change.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Final Call for Papers: Genealogies of Knowledge I</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/final-call-papers-genealogies-knowledge-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 15:18:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/final-call-papers-genealogies-knowledge-i/</guid>
      <description>Genealogies of Knowledge I: Translating Political and Scientific Thought across Time and Space The University of Manchester 7-9 December 2017 Final Call for Papers Hosted by the research team leading the AHRC-funded Genealogies of Knowledge project at the University of Manchester, this conference will provide a forum for engaging with questions of current import in relation to the role of translation in the production and circulation of political, scientific and other key concepts in social life across time and space… » Read more Conference News  Deadline for the submission of individual paper abstracts extended to 31 March by popular demand; Submission period for contributions to thematic panels now open; Full information on keynote speakers and their papers now available online.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call for Panel Papers: Science and Translation as Culturally Embedded Practices</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/call-panel-papers-science-translation-culturally-embedded-practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2017 16:03:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/call-panel-papers-science-translation-culturally-embedded-practices/</guid>
      <description>Genealogies of Knowledge I Translating Political and Scientific Thought across Time and Space University of Manchester 7-9 December 2017 Science and Translation as Culturally Embedded Practices Convenor: Maeve Olohan, University of Manchester Call for Panel Papers (Adobe PDF) Through the work of science studies, many scholars have come to understand science as culturally situated knowledge practices. This shift in understanding entailed a move away from thinking about science as the pursuit of universal truths and a debunking of the assumptions that science is unified and value-free.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call for Panel Papers: Dissemination, Contestation, and Mediation of Knowledge between Asia and the West</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/call-panel-papers-dissemination-contestation-mediation-knowledge-asia-west/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2017 15:20:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/call-panel-papers-dissemination-contestation-mediation-knowledge-asia-west/</guid>
      <description>Genealogies of Knowledge I Translating Political and Scientific Thought across Time and Space University of Manchester 7-9 December 2017 Dissemination, Contestation, and Mediation of Knowledge between Asia and the West Convenors: Kyung Hye Kim, Dang Li, Yifan Zhu (Shanghai Jiao Tong University) Call for Panel Papers (Adobe PDF) The dialogue between the West and the East continues to be decisively shaped by various processes of translation, where imported knowledge interacts with local knowledge in a dynamic cycle in which both are transformed to varying degrees.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call for Panel Papers: Translation and Health Humanities: The Role of Translated Personal Narratives in the Co-creation of Medical Knowledge</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/call-panel-papers-translation-health-humanities-role-translated-personal-narratives-co-creation-medical-knowledge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 13:58:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/call-panel-papers-translation-health-humanities-role-translated-personal-narratives-co-creation-medical-knowledge/</guid>
      <description>Genealogies of Knowledge I Translating Political and Scientific Thought across Time and Space University of Manchester 7-9 December 2017 Translation and Health Humanities: The Role of Translated Personal Narratives in the Co-creation of Medical Knowledge Convenor: Şebnem Susam-Saraeva University of Edinburgh Call for Panel Papers (Adobe PDF) Medicine, as an ‘applied science’, has traditionally enjoyed a particularly authoritative and powerful status within society. But while fast-paced scientific discoveries and technological innovations have improved the health of vast populations worldwide, some sections of society are becoming more and more disillusioned with what they regard as rigid, unholistic or wholesale treatments offered by the medical profession, and turning to alternative approaches to health and well-being.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Corpus Semiotics: Reassessing Context</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/corpus-semiotics-reassessing-context/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2017 14:36:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/corpus-semiotics-reassessing-context/</guid>
      <description>Corpus Semiotics: Reassessing Context Conference Room (C1. 18), Ellen Wilkinson Building, The University of Manchester 5 June 2017 In association with DH@Manchester Keynote Speaker: Professor Svenja Adolphs (University of Nottingham) Corpus analysis, in the tradition of Firth, Halliday and Sinclair, proceeds from the assumption that meaning arises from language in use, rather than language as an abstract system of relations, and hence that context is central to the interpretation of patterns revealed through the use of various tools of corpus analysis, especially concordancing software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Second Call for Papers: Genealogies of Knowledge I</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/second-call-papers-genealogies-knowledge-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2017 13:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/second-call-papers-genealogies-knowledge-i/</guid>
      <description>Genealogies of Knowledge I: Translating Political and Scientific Thought across Time and Space The University of Manchester 7-9 December 2017 Second Call for Papers The production and circulation of knowledge across temporal and cultural spaces is a well-established research theme among classicists and historians of political thought, ideas, science and medicine, but recent developments have opened up new perspectives on this area of study. The study of social knowledge flows has advanced our understanding of these transit processes in critical and productive ways.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kamran Karimullah</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/kamran-karimullah/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2017 14:14:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/kamran-karimullah/</guid>
      <description>I am the first of the Genealogies of Knowledge project’s senior post-doctoral researchers to be appointed. I received my Ph.D. from McGill University in 2014 in Islamic Philosophy. For the past three years I have worked with Peter E. Pormann on Arabic medicine on an ERC-funded project on the Arabic Commentaries on the Hippocratic Aphorisms (2012–2017). I am co-editing with Peter E. Pormann a special issue of Oriens 45.1–2 on the medical commentary tradition in medieval Islam.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call for Panel Papers: Lingua Francas of Knowledge</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/call-panel-papers-lingua-francas-knowledge/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2016 15:30:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/call-panel-papers-lingua-francas-knowledge/</guid>
      <description>Genealogies of Knowledge I Translating Political and Scientific Thought across Time and Space University of Manchester 7-9 December 2017 Lingua Francas of Knowledges Convenor: Karen Bennett Universidade Nova, Lisbon Call for Panel Papers (Adobe PDF) English is today the unrivalled vehicle for the transmission of knowledge, the language in which most scholarship is published, conferences are held, reading is done and lessons taught. However, its rise to prominence is a relatively recent development in the broad sweep of human history.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call for Panel Papers: The Magic of ‘Classical’ Languages Script, Sound and Sense in the Translation of Sacred Concepts</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/call-panel-papers-magic-classical-languages-script-sound-sense-translation-sacred-concepts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2016 14:48:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/call-panel-papers-magic-classical-languages-script-sound-sense-translation-sacred-concepts/</guid>
      <description>Genealogies of Knowledge I Translating Political and Scientific Thought across Time and Space University of Manchester 7-9 December 2017 The Magic of ‘Classical’ Languages Script, Sound and Sense in the Translation of Sacred Concepts Convenor: Hephzibah Israel University of Edinburgh Call for Panel Papers (Adobe PDF) What is the nature of a ‘sacred’ language? When we examine the translation of key concepts and texts across the spectrum of the so-called ‘World Religions’ we find that much of the nature of their transfer or circulation depends on certain conceptions of languages as sign systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Associate Position: Genealogies of Knowledge</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/research-associate-position-genealogies-knowledge/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2016 21:51:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/research-associate-position-genealogies-knowledge/</guid>
      <description>VACANCY REF: HUM-09286 Apply here: https://www.jobs.manchester.ac.uk/displayjob.aspx?jobid=12614 Application Deadline: Midnight 15 December 2016  Enquiries about the vacancy, shortlisting and interviews:  Professor Mona Baker (mona.baker@manchester.ac.uk) Professor Luis Pérez-González (luis.perez-gonzalez@manchester.ac.uk) Professor Peter E Pormann (peter.pormann@manchester.ac.uk)  General enquiries: hrservices@manchester.ac.uk Tel: +44 (0)161 275 4499 Technical support: universityofmanchester@helpmeapply.co.uk This vacancy will close for applications at midnight on 15 December 2016. slation Studies BACKGROUND The University of Manchester is the largest single-site university in the UK.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genealogies of Knowledge I: Translating Political and Scientific Thought across Time and Space</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/genealogies-knowledge-i-translating-political-scientific-thought-across-time-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2016 15:58:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/genealogies-knowledge-i-translating-political-scientific-thought-across-time-space/</guid>
      <description>7-9 December 2017 1st Call for Papers &amp;nbsp; The production and circulation of knowledge across temporal and cultural spaces is a well-established research theme among classicists and historians of political thought, ideas, science and medicine, but recent developments have opened up new perspectives on this area of study. The study of social knowledge flows has advanced our understanding of these transit processes in critical and productive ways. While earlier ‘diffusionist’ models of knowledge production and distribution were predicated on the ascendancy of European thought and science, and the treatment of other cultures as no more than producers of data to be collected, theorised and understood, emerging models of social knowledge foreground how the very process of circulation produces new knowledge and recognise the contribution of all actors and locations traversed by such flows over time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jan Buts</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/jan-buts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2016 14:19:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/jan-buts/</guid>
      <description>I am happy to introduce myself as the Genealogies of Knowledge project’s new Ph.D. Student. At my alma mater, KU Leuven, I was trained as a linguist and literary scholar, specialising in the Dutch and English languages. During my early educational years, I developed a keen interest in poetry and rhetorical narratology, research fields which I tended to approach through the lens of contemporary philosophy. After obtaining my Master’s degree in Western Literature, I worked as a research assistant for the Leuven-based MDRN research lab, where I was exposed to the literary production of the modernist period.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conference Announcement 2017</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/conference-announcement-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2016 13:48:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/conference-announcement-2017/</guid>
      <description>Plans for holding the first international conference organized by the Genealogies of Knowledge team are well under way. The conference is intended to provide a space for scholars from diverse disciplinary backgrounds to discuss various aspects of the impact of translation and other processes of mediation on the evolution of concepts across time and space. It will also provide an opportunity for engaging with current discourses that contest the foundations of political and scientific life, with methodological and theoretical issues relating to the use of large electronic corpora for tracing the evolution and contestation of concepts, and with the role of historical and modern lingua francas in constructing knowledge(s) across the full spectrum of human experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search and visualisation software tools</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/search-visualisation-software-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2016 13:37:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/search-visualisation-software-tools/</guid>
      <description>The Genealogies of Knowledge Corpus is supported by a set of powerful search and visualisation software tools that are being developed specifically for this project. Working with this software will allow the research team to trace the development and mutation of key concepts that have become a core part of our academic and public life, and their contestation and renegotiation by civil society today. Further technical information, examples and documentation are now available on the project website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Citizen Media and Public Spaces</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/citizen-media-public-spaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2016 10:57:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/citizen-media-public-spaces/</guid>
      <description>Citizen Media and Public Spaces  Diverse Expressions of Citizenship and Dissent Edited by Mona Baker and Bolette B. Blaagaard (2016, Routledge) Citizen Media and Public Spaces presents a pioneering exploration of citizen media as a highly interdisciplinary domain that raises vital political, social and ethical issues relating to conceptions of citizenship and state boundaries, the construction of publics and social imaginaries, processes of co-optation and reverse co-optation, power and resistance, the ethics of witnessing and solidarity, and novel responses to the democratic deficit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Congratulations to Luis Pérez-González</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/congratulations-luis-perez-gonzalez/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2016 17:09:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/congratulations-luis-perez-gonzalez/</guid>
      <description>&amp;nbsp; The Genealogies of Knowledge team is pleased to announce that one of its key members, Co-Investigator Luis Pérez-González, has been promoted to a Chair in Translation Studies at the University of Manchester, in recognition of his achievements in the field. Professor Pérez-González is a translation studies scholar with extensive experience in corpus-driven research and the study of citizen media and activism in the digital culture. He is leading the second strand of analysis on the Genealogies of Knowledge project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Associate: Genealogies of Knowledge (available from 1 January 2017 to 31 March 2020)</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/research-associate-genealogies-of-knowledge-available-from-1-january-2017-to-31-march-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2016 13:40:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/research-associate-genealogies-of-knowledge-available-from-1-january-2017-to-31-march-2020/</guid>
      <description>University of Manchester Closing date : 29/05/2016 Reference : HUM-08115 Genealogies of Knowledge: The Evolution and Contestation of Concepts across Time and Space is a 4-year, AHRC-funded project investigating the historical evolution and transformation through translation of key concepts in political and scientific thought that can often be traced back to the ancient Greek world, focusing on translations into early medieval Arabic, Latin and modern English. The research involves compiling large electronic corpora of texts and developing software applications to interrogate them and assist with the presentation of findings to other researchers and the public.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>