<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>books on Genealogies</title>
    <link>https://monabaker.org/tags/books/</link>
    <description>Recent content in books on Genealogies</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2017 14:56:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://monabaker.org/tags/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Humanities: Knowledge and Critique in a Digital Age</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/digital-humanities-knowledge-critique-digital-age/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2017 14:56:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/digital-humanities-knowledge-critique-digital-age/</guid>
      <description>David M. Berry, Anders Fagerjord As the twenty-first century unfolds, computers challenge the way in which we think about culture, society and what it is to be human: areas traditionally explored by the humanities. In a world of automation, Big Data, algorithms, Google searches, digital archives, real-time streams and social networks, our use of culture has been changing dramatically. The digital humanities give us powerful theories, methods and tools for exploring new ways of being in a digital age.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Languages and Culture in History</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/languages-culture-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2017 10:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/languages-culture-history/</guid>
      <description>The series Languages and Culture in History studies the role foreign languages have played in the creation of the linguistic and cultural heritage of Europe, both western and eastern, and at the individual, community, national or transnational level. At the heart of this series is the historical evolution of linguistic and cultural policies, internal as well as external, and their relationship with linguistic and cultural identities. The series takes an interdisciplinary approach to a variety of historical issues: the diffusion, the supply and the demand for foreign languages, the history of pedagogical practices, the historical relationship between languages in a given cultural context, the public and private use of foreign languages – in short, every way foreign languages intersect with local languages in the cultural realm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The construction of medieval Arab medicine</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/construction-medieval-arab-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2016 14:07:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/construction-medieval-arab-medicine/</guid>
      <description>The construction of medieval Arab medicine Edited by Pauline Koetschet and Peter E. Pormann (2016, Institut français du Proche-Orient) The history of pre-modern Arabic medicine remains shrouded in mystery, not because we would not have sources, but because in their majority, these sources have not been edited or studied. These are the sources that form the basis of the articles published in this book. These deal, inter alia, the transfer of medical knowledge and the construction of the Arab medicine from Greek sources, Indian, Persian and translated into Arabic, and the changes made to past medical knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magna Carta – 800 years on</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/magna-carta-800-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2016 13:49:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/magna-carta-800-years/</guid>
      <description>The Guardian&amp;nbsp;featured an article on theeight hundredth anniversary of Magna Carta in 2015 and the publication David Carpenter’s new translation of Magna Carta as a Penguin Classic, discussing scholarly work on the Magna Carta and its perceived and disputed historical and contemporary legacies.
 Magna Carta (Penguin Classics, David Carpenter, 2015)
 </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>