<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>media on Genealogies</title>
    <link>https://monabaker.org/tags/media/</link>
    <description>Recent content in media on Genealogies</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2018 13:17:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://monabaker.org/tags/media/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Genealogies of Knowledge Conference I (Dec. 2017): Video recordings now available</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/genealogies-of-knowledge-conference-i-dec-2017-video-recordings-now-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2018 13:17:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/genealogies-of-knowledge-conference-i-dec-2017-video-recordings-now-available/</guid>
      <description>The Genealogies of Knowledge project team is pleased to announce that video recordings of all six keynote presentations delivered during our first international conference last year in December 2017 are now available to view online. Please click on the links below to access these resources. Each speaker’s abstract and bio data can additionally be found here.  Keynote presentations &amp;nbsp;  Robert Wisnovsky,&#39;Commentaries, Translation and Philosophical Change: The Case of Greek-into-Arabic&#39; Marianne Maeckelbergh, &#39;The Practice of Unknowing: Knowledge Construction and Deconstruction in Social Movement Networks&#39; Eivind Engebretsen,&#39;Knowledge Translation (KT) as Bio-textual Crossings&#39; Edward Baring, ‘What’s Continental about Continental Philosophy?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Democracy, Futurity, and Security in Post-Coup Cairo (Video)</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/democracy-futurity-security-post-coup-cairo-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2017 09:54:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/democracy-futurity-security-post-coup-cairo-video/</guid>
      <description>Dr. Ian Alan Paul (Al-Quds Bard College, Abu Dis, Palestine) is a transdisciplinary artist, theorist, and curator. Drawing upon his fieldwork undertaken between 2013 and 2015, this event at the University of Manchester explored the myriad forms of contestation that emerged between the diverse legacies of the January 2011 uprising and the subsequent 2013 military coup in Cairo, Egypt. The presentation features sections of the online documentary The Conditions of Possibility (2016), reflections on the production of the documentary, and analysis of the competing forms of democratic possibility and suffocating security that continue to unfold in the present.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Translation and Contestation of Political and Scientific Concepts across Time and Space: A Corpus-Based Study</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/translation-contestation-political-scientific-concepts-across-time-space-corpus-based-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2016 14:16:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/translation-contestation-political-scientific-concepts-across-time-space-corpus-based-study/</guid>
      <description>Hong Kong Baptist University Library - Scholarly Talks Centre for Translation (18 February, 2016) &amp;nbsp;
 [siteorigin_widget class=&#34;WP_Widget_Media_Image&#34;][/siteorigin_widget]The Translation and Contestation of Political and Scientific Concepts across Time and Space: A Corpus-Based Study (Prof. Mona Baker)
This seminar introduced a large, interdisciplinary research project based at the University of Manchester in the UK and funded by the Arts and Humanities Research Council. The project involves compiling large electronic corpora of ancient Greek, medieval Arabic, Latin and Modern English to examine how central concepts in the humanities and sciences have been (re)translated into these three lingua francas, and how they have been interpreted and reinterpreted as they entered new cultural and temporal spaces.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>