<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>resources on Genealogies</title>
    <link>https://monabaker.org/tags/resources/</link>
    <description>Recent content in resources on Genealogies</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 13:38:25 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://monabaker.org/tags/resources/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Translating communities</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/translating-communities/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 13:38:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/translating-communities/</guid>
      <description>Katherine McDonald There’s been a lot of interesting discussion recently in the Classics Twitter-sphere about translation – and specifically about sexism in translation. Emily Wilson’s translation of the Odyssey has been the catalyst for a lot of this discussion, and she has been outspoken about the deficiencies that she sees in previous translations, including sexism and the erasure of slavery. This has all been very timely for me, because for the first time I’m creating my own translations of literary and historical texts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Research Tool For Classical Scholars</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/digital-research-tool-for-classical-scholars/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 09:55:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/digital-research-tool-for-classical-scholars/</guid>
      <description>Digital Corpus of Literary Papyri provides access to fragments of ancient literature The Digital Corpus of Literary Papyri (DCLP), a new digital tool for researching ancient literature, is now available. Scholars from Heidelberg University and New York University (USA) spearheaded the development of the newly released open-access database, which offers information about and transcripts of Greek and Latin texts preserved on fragments of papyri, but also, for example, on ceramic shards or wooden tablets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exile, refuge and the Greek polis: between justice and humanity</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/exile-refuge-greek-polis-justice-humanity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 13:51:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/exile-refuge-greek-polis-justice-humanity/</guid>
      <description>Exile, refuge and the Greek polis: between justice and humanity Dr. Benjamin Gray 20 February 2015  This seminar addresses the place of exiles and refugees in the Greek polis (city-state), with a focus on the later Classical and Hellenistic periods (c. 400-100 B.C.). It addresses the different forms of protection and aid granted by Greek poleis and their citizens to Greeks displaced through war and civil strife. It also analyses the range of arguments advanced by ancient Greeks for protecting or helping exiles and refugees, including the self-presentation of displaced Greeks themselves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The transmission of Greek philosophy and medicine</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/transmission-greek-philosophy-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2017 15:44:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/transmission-greek-philosophy-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Aileen Das | British Library blog Link: https://www.bl.uk/greek-manuscripts/articles/the-transmission-of-greek-philosophy-and-medicine   Ancient Greek philosophy and medical writing were extremely influential on later thought, both in the West and in the East. Aileen Das traces some of the strands of this remarkable journey, from Greek to Syriac, Arabic, and Latin.   Severus Sebokht (d. 666/667 CE) writes: [Philosophy] does not belong to the Greeks alone, but can be acquired by all who are diligent, whether they are Greeks or Barbarians.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Truth in translation</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/truth-in-translation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 09:31:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/truth-in-translation/</guid>
      <description>Jane Gallagher John Rylands Library Special Collections Blog 19 September, 2017 https://rylandscollections.wordpress.com/2017/09/19/truth-in-translation/amp/ How do you define truth? In medieval Europe, it was often thought that truth came from ancient texts in Latin or Greek, passed down through generations and only accessible to those who could read them. The truth in these texts could then be spoken to others who couldn’t read, or didn’t understand ancient languages. And few texts were more important in European society than the Bible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cairn International Monthly Dossier</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/cairn-international-monthly-dossier/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 08:56:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/cairn-international-monthly-dossier/</guid>
      <description>Cairn International | 14 June 2017 Link: http://www.cairn-int.info/dossiers   Cairn International&#39;s Monthly Dossier is a free email publication, in English, looking at current events through the prism of francophone scholarly publishing. The ambition of Cairn’s Monthly Dossiers is to draw your attention to what’s being published in the francophone world in the fields of social sciences and humanities by providing a practical and global context to the work of selected scholars.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Body in Translation - Translation, the Human body and Early Modern Demarcations of Knowledge</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/body-translation-translation-human-body-early-modern-demarcations-knowledge/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2016 10:02:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/body-translation-translation-human-body-early-modern-demarcations-knowledge/</guid>
      <description>This project examines how different kinds of human bodies were constituted through translation in medical, ethnographic and religious discourses in the early modern global world. The project aims to historicize present notions of translation by analysing a test case at the interstices of nature and culture. It examines how different kinds of human bodies were constituted through translation in medical, ethnographic and religious discourses in the early modern global world. It is concerned with conceptual and physical dimensions of the human body, and how these intersect with translation as a practice and a concept.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing Human Rights and Getting It Wrong</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/writing-human-rights-getting-wrong/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2016 10:18:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/writing-human-rights-getting-wrong/</guid>
      <description>Alex de Waal Boston Review: June 06, 2016 http://bostonreview.net/world/alex-de-waal-writing-human-rights The power to accuse someone of a grave crime on the basis of hearsay is a heady one. I have done it, and I faced the consequences of being wrong. Twenty years ago in the Nuba Mountains of central Sudan, I met a man, Chief Hussein Karbus, whose murder I had reported three years earlier. He was introduced to me by the man I had accused of ordering his death, a leader of the Sudan People’s Liberation Army.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arabic and Latin Glossary</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/arabic-latin-glossary/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2016 08:48:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/arabic-latin-glossary/</guid>
      <description>The Arabic and Latin Glossary is a dictionary of the vocabulary of the Arabic–Latin translations of the Middle Ages. It unites the entries of all existing Arabic–Latin glossaries in modern editions of medieval works. The Glossary has a double aim: to improve our understanding of the Arabic influence in Europe, especially with respect to scientific vocabulary, and to provide a lexical tool for the understanding of Arabic and Latin scientific texts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Democracy Emerges from the Spaces In Between</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/democracy-emerges-from-the-spaces-in-between/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2016 20:13:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/democracy-emerges-from-the-spaces-in-between/</guid>
      <description>David Graeber There Never Was a West Or, Democracy Emerges From the Spaces In Between  Part I: On the Incoherence Of the Notion of the “Western Tradition”
Parenthetical Note: On the Slipperiness of the Western Eye
World-Systems Reconfigured
Part II: Democracy Was Not Invented
Part III: On the Emergence of the “Democratic Ideal”
Part IV: Recuperation
The “Influence Debate”
Traditions as Acts of Endless Refoundation
Part V: The Crisis of the State</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arabic and Persian Medical Books and Manuscripts</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/arabic-and-persian-medical-books-and-manuscripts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2016 14:57:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/arabic-and-persian-medical-books-and-manuscripts/</guid>
      <description>This digitized collection of selected volumes of medical books and manuscripts, dating from 1300 to 1921, is drawn from theMedical Historical Library, Cushing/Whitney Medical Library. This collection reflects the Arabic and Persian intellectual efforts that translated, augmented, and transmitted Greek and Roman medical knowledge to Western societies during the Renaissance. It includes iconic works by authors such as Avicenna and al-Razi. The Medical Historical Library, originally formed by the joining of three collections by bibliophiles Harvey Cushing, John Fulton, and Arnold Klebs, has over 120,000 volumes dating from the 12th to the 21st centuries.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>