<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>news on Genealogies</title>
    <link>https://monabaker.org/tags/news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in news on Genealogies</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 09:55:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://monabaker.org/tags/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Research Tool For Classical Scholars</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/digital-research-tool-for-classical-scholars/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 09:55:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/digital-research-tool-for-classical-scholars/</guid>
      <description>Digital Corpus of Literary Papyri provides access to fragments of ancient literature The Digital Corpus of Literary Papyri (DCLP), a new digital tool for researching ancient literature, is now available. Scholars from Heidelberg University and New York University (USA) spearheaded the development of the newly released open-access database, which offers information about and transcripts of Greek and Latin texts preserved on fragments of papyri, but also, for example, on ceramic shards or wooden tablets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>German academy launches project to document Arab and Islamic heritage</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/german-academy-launches-project-document-arab-islamic-heritage/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 12:09:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/german-academy-launches-project-document-arab-islamic-heritage/</guid>
      <description>The Saxon Academy of Sciences in Leipzig, Germany has launched a digital platform to document millions of books and manuscripts from the Arab and Islamic world. The platform named The Arab Library was launched earlier this week, providing researchers and academics access to rare and original historical texts. The project is scheduled to run until 2036, with the possibility of its work being extended if demand exists. A budget of €7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emerging Democracies Postdoctoral Fellowship</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/emerging-democracies-postdoctoral-fellowship/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2016 09:45:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/emerging-democracies-postdoctoral-fellowship/</guid>
      <description>Fellowship period: September 2017 – May 2018 Application deadline: January 15, 2017 The Weiser Center for Emerging Democracies (WCED) at the University of Michigan invites postdoctoral scholars to apply for the Emerging Democracies Postdoctoral Fellowship. The fellowship supports research on the broad historical, political, economic, and societal conditions under which democracies emerge—and autocracies endure. Three awards are available in 2017-18. Emerging Democracies Postdoctoral Fellows are expected to focus on their own research, participate in WCED workshops and events, and present one public lecture during their fellowship year, while in residence at the University of Michigan, Ann Arbor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Tenth Annual Intensive Introduction to Islamic Codicology</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/tenth-annual-intensive-introduction-islamic-codicology/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2016 10:46:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/tenth-annual-intensive-introduction-islamic-codicology/</guid>
      <description>3–7 October 2016 Cambridge University Library, Cambridge, UK The Islamic Manuscript Association, together with the Thesaurus Islamicus Foundation, Cambridge University Library, and the University of Cambridge&#39;s HRH Prince Alwaleed Bin Talal Centre of Islamic Studies, announces its Tenth Annual Intensive Introduction to Islamic Codicology Course, which will be held from 3-7 October 2016 at the Cambridge University Library. This intensive five-day course will introduce the study of Islamic manuscript codices as physical objects, or the archaeology of the Islamic book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Human Rights, Society and Multi-Level Governance Scholarship</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/human-rights-society-multi-level-governance-scholarship/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2016 10:06:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/human-rights-society-multi-level-governance-scholarship/</guid>
      <description>Western Sydney University has advertised a joint Ph. D. program coordinated by the University of Padova in Italy. The aim of the program is to develop researchers with a multi/interdisciplinary profile. The program includes research and training in the area of human rights studies, covering the various legal, social, philosophical and economic approaches and methodologies and different geographical areas. The successful candidate will be based at Western Sydney University, and will have the opportunity to study for at least one semester in Croatia, Greece or Italy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Corpus Linguistics: Method, Analysis, Interpretation</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/corpus-linguistics-method-analysis-interpretation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2016 08:52:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/corpus-linguistics-method-analysis-interpretation/</guid>
      <description>The Future Learn platform has introduced an online course developed by Lancaster University. The course offers a practical introduction to the methodology of corpus linguistics for researchers in social sciences and humanities. The course aims to:  Equip those taking the course with skills necessary for collecting and analysing large digital collections of text (corpora); Provide educational support for those who want to use the corpus method; demonstrate the use of corpus linguistics in the humanities, especially History Give a sense of the incredibly wide uses that corpora have been put to; Allow those with an interest in language, who have not heard of the corpus approach before, a new way of looking at language; Demonstrate that corpus approaches to social science can offer valuable insight into social reality by investigating the use and manipulation of language in society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How a thousand years of Arabic scholarship advanced scientific debate</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/thousand-years-arabic-scholarship-advanced-scientific-debate/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2016 09:23:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/thousand-years-arabic-scholarship-advanced-scientific-debate/</guid>
      <description>The Guardian recently featured an article including examples of important manuscripts illustrating how, from the ninth to the nineteenth centuries, scholars and scribes used Arabic as a lingua franca to debate and develop scientific ideas. Arabic-speaking scholars translated classical Greek, Persian and even Sanskrit texts on topics such as medicine, mathematics and astronomy. These scholars went far beyond translation and preservation and fostered a unique and vibrant scientific culture within the Arabic-speaking world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Toledo Translation Fund: Call for Donations</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/the-toledo-translation-fund-call-for-donations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2016 18:46:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/the-toledo-translation-fund-call-for-donations/</guid>
      <description>By Rosie Warren / 15 January 2016
The Toledo Translation Fund was established to support the translation into English of major works in the humanities and social sciences, from a wide range of world languages and cultures. Named after the twelfth- and thirteenth-century Toledo School of Translators—whose translations of philosophical and scientific treatises from Arabic, Greek and Hebrew paved the way for the Renaissance—Toledo Translation Fund projects will focus on texts that are sure to be of enduring value.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>