<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Genealogies</title>
    <link>https://monabaker.org/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Genealogies</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 08:26:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://monabaker.org/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Registration now open: Constructing the ‘Public Intellectual’ in the Premodern World</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/registration-now-open-constructing-the-public-intellectual-in-the-premodern-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 08:26:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/registration-now-open-constructing-the-public-intellectual-in-the-premodern-world/</guid>
      <description>Constructing the ‘Public Intellectual’ in the Premodern World A two-day conference co-hosted by the Genealogies of Knowledge project, the Division of Classics, Ancient History and Archaeology, and the Centre for Translation and Intercultural Studies, University of Manchester, UK 5th-6th September 2019 | Chancellors Hotel, Manchester  Call for papers Keynote speakers&amp;nbsp;Important dates
Venue Registration&amp;nbsp;Bursaries Contact
Abstracts
 Registration now open We are pleased to announce that registration for this event is now open.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Edoardo Crisafulli – Demystifying Christian Liberty</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/edoardo-crisafulli-demystifying-christian-liberty/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 15:44:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/edoardo-crisafulli-demystifying-christian-liberty/</guid>
      <description>Demystifying Christian Liberty Edoardo Crisafulli 1 May 2019, 5pm-6.30pm Ellen Wilkinson Building, Room B2.4 University of Manchester  On 1 May 2019, the Genealogies of Knowledge team will be hosting a talk by Dr Edoardo Crisafulli entitled ‘Demystifying Christian Liberty’. No registration is necessary, all are very welcome to attend! &amp;nbsp; Abstract This presentation delves into one of the most hotly debated issues in contemporary political philosophy, and a potential source of conflict in political discourse: the tense and complex relationship between liberalism and Christianity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genealogies of Knowledge II</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/genealogies-of-knowledge-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2019 15:23:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/genealogies-of-knowledge-ii/</guid>
      <description>An international conference hosted by the Centre for Translation and the Translation Programme, Hong Kong Baptist University, Hong Kong
In collaboration with the&amp;nbsp;Genealogies of Knowledge Project, University of Manchester, UK
7-9 April 2020
 CONFERENCE THEME&amp;nbsp;KEYNOTE SPEAKERS VENUE IMPORTANT DATES&amp;nbsp;ABSTRACT / PANEL SUBMISSION
 Conference Theme This conference builds on and extends the theme of Genealogies of Knowledge I, which was held in Manchester in December 2017 and focused on the role of translation in the production and circulation of political, scientific and other key concepts in social life across time and space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genealogies of Knowledge Conference I (Dec. 2017): Video recordings now available</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/genealogies-of-knowledge-conference-i-dec-2017-video-recordings-now-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2018 13:17:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/genealogies-of-knowledge-conference-i-dec-2017-video-recordings-now-available/</guid>
      <description>The Genealogies of Knowledge project team is pleased to announce that video recordings of all six keynote presentations delivered during our first international conference last year in December 2017 are now available to view online. Please click on the links below to access these resources. Each speaker’s abstract and bio data can additionally be found here.  Keynote presentations &amp;nbsp;  Robert Wisnovsky,&#39;Commentaries, Translation and Philosophical Change: The Case of Greek-into-Arabic&#39; Marianne Maeckelbergh, &#39;The Practice of Unknowing: Knowledge Construction and Deconstruction in Social Movement Networks&#39; Eivind Engebretsen,&#39;Knowledge Translation (KT) as Bio-textual Crossings&#39; Edward Baring, ‘What’s Continental about Continental Philosophy?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CFP: Translation as Political Act</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/cfp-translation-as-political-act/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 16:22:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/cfp-translation-as-political-act/</guid>
      <description>Translation as Political Act Perugia, Italy 9-11 May 2019 A three-day conference hosted by the Dipartimento di Scienze Politiche, University of Perugia, Italy in collaboration with the Genealogies of Knowledge project. Conference website: http://home.translationaspoliticalact.net/ Confirmed speakers include: Mona Baker, Nicole Doerr, Fruela Fernandez, Lynne Franjié, Guy Rooryck and Lieve Jooken.  Call for Papers  Version française Versione italiana  Translation, both in the restricted sense of interlinguistic rewriting and the broader sense of a set of cultural and political activities, has increasingly featured in studies promoting a critical understanding of the development of political ideas and of global history.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Constructing the ‘Public Intellectual’ in the Premodern World</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/4375/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2018 12:53:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/4375/</guid>
      <description>Constructing the &#39;Public Intellectual&#39; in the Premodern World A two-day conference co-hosted by the Genealogies of Knowledge project, the Division of Classics, Ancient History and Archaeology, and the Centre for Translation and Intercultural Studies, University of Manchester, UK
5th-6th September 2019 | Chancellors Hotel, Manchester
 Call for papers Keynote speakers&amp;nbsp;Important dates
Venue Registration&amp;nbsp;Bursaries Contact
Abstracts
 Abstract submission now closed:&amp;nbsp; Please note that the deadline for submitting an abstract for this conference has now passed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Translation and conceptual change: The historical development of jiao 教 in Chinese and its impact on the concept of ‘religion’ in English scholarship</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/translation-and-conceptual-change-the-historical-development-of-jiao-%e6%95%99-in-chinese-and-its-impact-on-the-concept-of-religion-in-english-scholar/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 15:22:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/translation-and-conceptual-change-the-historical-development-of-jiao-%e6%95%99-in-chinese-and-its-impact-on-the-concept-of-religion-in-english-scholar/</guid>
      <description>The historical development of jiao 教 in Chinese and its impact on the concept of ‘religion’ in English scholarship I-Hsin Chen | The Chinese University of Hong Kong Translation and Interpreting Studies, 13(2): 317–336. Link: https://benjamins.com/catalog/tis.13.2   ABSTRACT: This article contends that the traditional Chinese concept of jiao (teaching) has, through translation, greatly influenced the conceptual development of ‘religion’ in English-language scholarship. The article first demonstrates how the historical development of jiao in Chinese reveals numerous previously neglected patterns of Chinese spirituality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Translation and conceptual change: Consequences of the conflation of xiao and filial piety in English</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/translation-and-conceptual-change-consequences-of-the-conflation-of-xiao-and-filial-piety-in-english/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 15:19:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/translation-and-conceptual-change-consequences-of-the-conflation-of-xiao-and-filial-piety-in-english/</guid>
      <description>Consequences of the conflation of xiao and filial piety in English James St. André | The Chinese University of Hong Kong Translation and Interpreting Studies, 13(2): 293–316. Link: https://benjamins.com/catalog/tis.13.2   ABSTRACT: This article examines the development over time of the English expression “filial piety” in order to document how, at least partly in response to pressure from an equivalence that is established with the Chinese term xiao (孝) in the seventeenth century, the term takes on new and increasingly negative connotations in English.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Translating communities</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/translating-communities/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 13:38:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/translating-communities/</guid>
      <description>Katherine McDonald There’s been a lot of interesting discussion recently in the Classics Twitter-sphere about translation – and specifically about sexism in translation. Emily Wilson’s translation of the Odyssey has been the catalyst for a lot of this discussion, and she has been outspoken about the deficiencies that she sees in previous translations, including sexism and the erasure of slavery. This has all been very timely for me, because for the first time I’m creating my own translations of literary and historical texts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Palestinian Animal League (PAL) reports on &#39;Developing and Translating Rights&#39; event</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/the-palestinian-animal-league-pal-reports-on-developing-and-translating-rights-event/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 11:47:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/the-palestinian-animal-league-pal-reports-on-developing-and-translating-rights-event/</guid>
      <description>The blog post reproduced below was written by a member of the Palestinian Animal League (PAL). It reports on the recent Developing and Translating Rights event, hosted by the Genealogies of Knowledge project and held at the University of Manchester on 19th June 2018.  PAL in UK PAL was pleased to be invited to an event organised by the Centre for Translation and Intercultural Studies (https://www.alc.manchester.ac.uk/ctis/) at the University of Manchester (http://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genealogies of Knowledge Software - Developments and Enhancements</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/genealogies-of-knowledge-software-developments-and-enhancements/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 09:14:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/genealogies-of-knowledge-software-developments-and-enhancements/</guid>
      <description>The Genealogies of Knowledge project has recently announced the release of the GoK corpus browser interface for researchers wishing to work with the range of corpora developed as part of this project. This is a substantial resource which is constantly being expanded. It currently consists of the following sections:  Modern English Corpus: 17,757,212 tokens Internet English Corpus: 1,201,414 tokens Classical Greek Corpus: 2,763,315 tokens Early Latin Corpus: 866,462 tokens Medieval Arabic Corpus: 1,545,223 tokens  New Features New functionalities have also now been added to the main concordancing interface: Once you have generated a concordance, you can now delete a line by clicking on the Delete Line button in the right-hand corner of the screen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A host of tongues.. Multilingualism, lingua franca and translation in the Early Modern period</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/a-host-of-tongues-multilingualism-lingua-franca-and-translation-in-the-early-modern-period/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2018 14:42:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/a-host-of-tongues-multilingualism-lingua-franca-and-translation-in-the-early-modern-period/</guid>
      <description>Call for Papers 13-15 December 2018 Faculty of Humanities and Social Sciences, Nova University of Lisbon  Conference Website  In the fifteenth and sixteenth centuries, the linguistic situation in Europe was one of remarkable fluidity. Latin, the great scholarly lingua franca of the medieval period, was beginning to crack as the tectonic plates shifted beneath it, but the vernaculars had not yet crystallized into the national languages that they would become a century later, and bi- or multilingualism was still rife.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Research Tool For Classical Scholars</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/digital-research-tool-for-classical-scholars/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 09:55:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/digital-research-tool-for-classical-scholars/</guid>
      <description>Digital Corpus of Literary Papyri provides access to fragments of ancient literature The Digital Corpus of Literary Papyri (DCLP), a new digital tool for researching ancient literature, is now available. Scholars from Heidelberg University and New York University (USA) spearheaded the development of the newly released open-access database, which offers information about and transcripts of Greek and Latin texts preserved on fragments of papyri, but also, for example, on ceramic shards or wooden tablets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#39;Developing and Translating Rights&#39; event</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/developing-translating-rights-event/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 09:05:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/developing-translating-rights-event/</guid>
      <description>Developing and Translating Rights A half-day event co-hosted by the Genealogies of Knowledge Project and the Centre for Translation and Intercultural Studies, University of Manchester, UK
19 June 2018 | Ellen Wilkinson Building, University of Manchester
 Programme&amp;nbsp;Abstracts&amp;nbsp;Registration&amp;nbsp;Venue&amp;nbsp;Contact
 About the event The concept of human rights, as enshrined in the UN Declaration of Human Rights, itself translated into more than 501 languages (www.un.org/en), has been gradually expanded to encompass a broad range of specific rights, including civil, cultural, economic, environmental and social rights.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exile, refuge and the Greek polis: between justice and humanity</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/exile-refuge-greek-polis-justice-humanity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 13:51:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/exile-refuge-greek-polis-justice-humanity/</guid>
      <description>Exile, refuge and the Greek polis: between justice and humanity Dr. Benjamin Gray 20 February 2015  This seminar addresses the place of exiles and refugees in the Greek polis (city-state), with a focus on the later Classical and Hellenistic periods (c. 400-100 B.C.). It addresses the different forms of protection and aid granted by Greek poleis and their citizens to Greeks displaced through war and civil strife. It also analyses the range of arguments advanced by ancient Greeks for protecting or helping exiles and refugees, including the self-presentation of displaced Greeks themselves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Corpora and Discourse International Conference</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/corpora-discourse-international-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2018 10:49:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/corpora-discourse-international-conference/</guid>
      <description>Call for Papers 22-24 June 2018 Lancaster University The fourth international Corpora and Discourse conference (CAD 2018) will be held at Lancaster University from Friday 22 June to Sunday 24 June 2018. The conference will be hosted by the ESRC Centre for Corpus Approaches to Social Science (CASS). Corpus-Assisted Discourse Studies (CADS) investigates the employment of corpus techniques to examine how language is used in social contexts for communicative purposes. Corpus linguistics is a powerful methodology – a way of using computers to assist the analysis of language so that regularities among many millions of words can be quickly and accurately identified.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>German academy launches project to document Arab and Islamic heritage</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/german-academy-launches-project-document-arab-islamic-heritage/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 12:09:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/german-academy-launches-project-document-arab-islamic-heritage/</guid>
      <description>The Saxon Academy of Sciences in Leipzig, Germany has launched a digital platform to document millions of books and manuscripts from the Arab and Islamic world. The platform named The Arab Library was launched earlier this week, providing researchers and academics access to rare and original historical texts. The project is scheduled to run until 2036, with the possibility of its work being extended if demand exists. A budget of €7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>‘Mutations in Citizenship’ event (23 March 2018)</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/registration-now-open-mutations-citizenship-event-23-march-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2017 15:53:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/registration-now-open-mutations-citizenship-event-23-march-2018/</guid>
      <description>‘Mutations in Citizenship’:&amp;nbsp; Activist and translational perspectives on migration and mobility in the age of globalisation A&amp;nbsp;research symposium co-hosted by the Genealogies of Knowledge project and the Centre for Translation and Intercultural Studies, University of Manchester, UK
23&amp;nbsp;March 2018 | Kanaris Theatre, Manchester Museum
 &amp;nbsp; Programme&amp;nbsp;Abstracts&amp;nbsp;Venue&amp;nbsp;Registration&amp;nbsp;Contact  About the event Migration has always played an important role in the history and development of human societies, but the past fifty years have seen marked rises in the movement and mobility of diverse populations worldwide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CFP: Using Corpora in Contrastive and Translation Studies (5th edition)</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/cfp-using-corpora-contrastive-translation-studies-5th-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 16:59:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/cfp-using-corpora-contrastive-translation-studies-5th-edition/</guid>
      <description>&amp;nbsp; The Centre for English Corpus Linguistics of the University of Louvain is organizing the fifth edition of the Using Corpora in Contrastive and Translation Studies conference series in Louvain-la-Neuve (Belgium) on 12-14 September, 2018.  UCCTS is a biennial international conference which was launched by Richard Xiao in 2008 to provide an international forum for the exploration of the theoretical and practical issues pertaining to the creation and use of corpora in contrastive and translation/interpreting studies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Re-Imagining Cultural Histories of The Middle East and North Africa</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/re-imagining-cultural-histories-middle-east-north-africa/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 11:51:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/re-imagining-cultural-histories-middle-east-north-africa/</guid>
      <description>Call for Papers 28 June 2018 SOAS, University of London A conference organised by:  Communication and Media Research Institute, University of Westminster; The Centre for Global Media and Communications, SOAS; Goldsmiths College, University of London; Middle East and North Africa Programme, Chatham House.  To celebrate 10 years of the Middle East Journal of Culture and Communication. Confirmed keynote: Professor Ella Shohat, New York University The Arab uprisings of 2011 have awakened interest in studies of cultural creativity and transformations across different historical epochs in the Middle East and North Africa region.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The transmission of Greek philosophy and medicine</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/transmission-greek-philosophy-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2017 15:44:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/transmission-greek-philosophy-medicine/</guid>
      <description>Aileen Das | British Library blog Link: https://www.bl.uk/greek-manuscripts/articles/the-transmission-of-greek-philosophy-and-medicine   Ancient Greek philosophy and medical writing were extremely influential on later thought, both in the West and in the East. Aileen Das traces some of the strands of this remarkable journey, from Greek to Syriac, Arabic, and Latin.   Severus Sebokht (d. 666/667 CE) writes: [Philosophy] does not belong to the Greeks alone, but can be acquired by all who are diligent, whether they are Greeks or Barbarians.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>‘Mutations in Citizenship’:  Activist and translational perspectives on migration and mobility  in the age of globalisation</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/mutations-citizenship-activist-translational-perspectives-migration-mobility-age-globalisation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 17:42:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/mutations-citizenship-activist-translational-perspectives-migration-mobility-age-globalisation/</guid>
      <description>&amp;nbsp; A research symposium co-hosted by the Genealogies of Knowledge project and the Centre for Translation and Intercultural Studies, University of Manchester, UK 23rd March 2018  Migration has always played an important role in the history and development of human societies, but the past fifty years have seen marked rises in the movement and mobility of diverse populations worldwide. An unprecedented 244 million people now live in a country other than that in which they were born, a figure which has already increased by 41 percent since the start of the new millennium (UN Sustainable Development 2016).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conference Programme: Genealogies of Knowledge I  2017</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/conference-programme-genealogies-knowledge-i-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 10:28:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/conference-programme-genealogies-knowledge-i-2017/</guid>
      <description>Genealogies of Knowledge I: Translating Political and Scientific Thought across Time and Space The University of Manchester 7-9 December 2017 Conference Programme The full programme of the Genealogies of Knowledge 2017 Conference can now be viewed and downloaded from the conference website, in both outline and detailed versions: http://genealogiesofknowledge.net/gok2017conference/programme/ Hosted by the research team leading the AHRC-funded Genealogies of Knowledge project at the University of Manchester, this conference will provide a forum for engaging with questions of current import in relation to the role of translation in the production and circulation of political, scientific and other key concepts in social life across time and space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Governance and Public Health in Early Nineteenth-Century Egypt</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/governance-public-health-early-nineteenth-century-egypt/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2017 09:44:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/governance-public-health-early-nineteenth-century-egypt/</guid>
      <description>Institute for the Study of Muslim Civilisations, London October 19, 2017 Part of DIALOGUES 2017: a thought-provoking series of seminars on governance in Muslim contexts The Governance Programme at the Aga Khan University&#39;s Institute for the Study of Muslim Civilisations is hosting Governance and Public Health in Early Nineteenth-Century Egypt in the fourth seminar of its 2017 Dialogues Series. Dr. Kamran Karimullah will explore the role that medical practice and medical discourse played in the historical evolution of political power and society in nineteenth-century Egypt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Challenge and Promise of Interdisciplinarity</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/challenge-and-promise-of-interdisciplinarity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2017 16:16:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/challenge-and-promise-of-interdisciplinarity/</guid>
      <description>Researching Translation and Interpreting I The Challenge and Promise of Interdisciplinarity 13-15 October 2017 School of Foreign Languages, Shanghai Jiao Tong University, Shanghai, China First Call for Papers A relative newcomer to the academic world and initially associated with vocational training, translation studies is now firmly established as a vibrant research field in many if not most universities around the world. In their various modes and diverse manifestations, translation and interpreting have further engaged scholars located well beyond the boundaries of translation studies – including sociologists, media and film specialists, forensic linguists, literary scholars and political scientists.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ARTIS@COLOGNE 2017</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/artiscologne-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2017 09:47:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/artiscologne-2017/</guid>
      <description>ARTIS Training Event: Corpora in translation and interpreting studies Cologne University of Applied Sciences (TH Köln) 26 October 2017 An ARTIS onsite training event hosted by the Institute of Translation and Multilingual Communication About the event Building on the success of the Translation Research Summer Schools, run by the University of Manchester, the University of Edinburgh and University College London, ARTIS (Advancing Research in Translation and Interpreting Studies) is an international network which supports the training requirements of doctoral students, postdoctoral and early career researchers in translation and interpreting studies, as well as supporting both junior and experienced teaching staff who wish to develop or refresh their research skills.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Truth in translation</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/truth-in-translation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 09:31:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/truth-in-translation/</guid>
      <description>Jane Gallagher John Rylands Library Special Collections Blog 19 September, 2017 https://rylandscollections.wordpress.com/2017/09/19/truth-in-translation/amp/ How do you define truth? In medieval Europe, it was often thought that truth came from ancient texts in Latin or Greek, passed down through generations and only accessible to those who could read them. The truth in these texts could then be spoken to others who couldn’t read, or didn’t understand ancient languages. And few texts were more important in European society than the Bible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arabographic Optical Character Recognition (OCR)</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/arabographic-optical-character-recognition-ocr/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2017 10:06:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/arabographic-optical-character-recognition-ocr/</guid>
      <description>The OpenITI team, building on the foundational open-source OCR work of Leipzig University’s Alexander von Humboldt Chair for Digital Humanities, has reported Optical Character Recognition (OCR) percentage accuracy rates for classical Arabic-script texts in the high nineties. These numbers are based on tests of seven different Arabic-script texts of varying quality and typefaces, totaling over 7,000 lines (approx. 400 pages, 87,000 words). These accuracy rates not only represent a distinct improvement over the actual accuracy rates of the various proprietary OCR options for classical Arabic-script texts, but, equally important, they are produced using an open-source OCR software called Kraken (developed by Benjamin Kiessling, Leipzig University), that is to be made freely available to the broader Islamic, Persian, and Arabic Studies communities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Translation in the pre-modern world</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/translation-pre-modern-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2017 12:51:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/translation-pre-modern-world/</guid>
      <description>Karla Mallette Middle Eastern Literatures, 2017 Abstract Translation occupies a central place in current theories of world literature, but it is not the only way in which texts circulate beyond their original cultural and temporal contexts to become world literature. This article explores the shifting relationship between language and territory, contrasting modern languages as territorially bound by the nation-state with pre-modern cosmopolitan languages that transcended territorial location. Drawing upon the complex translation process of the works of Aristotle from the Abbasid translation movement of the eighth through 10th centuries to the multiple print editions of competing translations of Aristotle’s works published in Venice in the 16th century, the article argues that world literature often results from the confluence of the broad reach of a cosmopolitan language and the mobility of translation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Democracy, Futurity, and Security in Post-Coup Cairo (Video)</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/democracy-futurity-security-post-coup-cairo-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2017 09:54:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/democracy-futurity-security-post-coup-cairo-video/</guid>
      <description>Dr. Ian Alan Paul (Al-Quds Bard College, Abu Dis, Palestine) is a transdisciplinary artist, theorist, and curator. Drawing upon his fieldwork undertaken between 2013 and 2015, this event at the University of Manchester explored the myriad forms of contestation that emerged between the diverse legacies of the January 2011 uprising and the subsequent 2013 military coup in Cairo, Egypt. The presentation features sections of the online documentary The Conditions of Possibility (2016), reflections on the production of the documentary, and analysis of the competing forms of democratic possibility and suffocating security that continue to unfold in the present.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What was Philology in Arabic?</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/what-was-philology-in-arabic/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2017 10:28:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/what-was-philology-in-arabic/</guid>
      <description>Thursday 13 July - Saturday 15 July 2017 Freie Universität Berlin The international conference will investigate the neglected history of Arabic-Islamic textual practices and interpretative methods in the early modern world from a global and comparative perspective. Although philology has always been a global knowledge practice, no such account of its history has ever been written. Indeed, wherever texts exist, a method of making sense of them has existed as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cairn International Monthly Dossier</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/cairn-international-monthly-dossier/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 08:56:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/cairn-international-monthly-dossier/</guid>
      <description>Cairn International | 14 June 2017 Link: http://www.cairn-int.info/dossiers   Cairn International&#39;s Monthly Dossier is a free email publication, in English, looking at current events through the prism of francophone scholarly publishing. The ambition of Cairn’s Monthly Dossiers is to draw your attention to what’s being published in the francophone world in the fields of social sciences and humanities by providing a practical and global context to the work of selected scholars.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Members of Genealogies of Knowledge Project Advisory Board</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/new-members-genealogies-knowledge-project-advisory-board/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 10:32:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/new-members-genealogies-knowledge-project-advisory-board/</guid>
      <description>We are pleased to announce that three colleagues from Manchester University have recently joined the Genealogies of Knowledge Project Advisory Board:
 Stuart Jones Stuart Jones is Professor of Intellectual History at the University of Manchester. His research interests focus on the history of political thought and of political concepts in modern Europe, on the history of universities, and on the emergent field of the history of the humanities. He is the author of The French State in Question (1993), Victorian Political Thought (2000), and Intellect and Character in Victorian England: Mark Pattison and the Invention of the Don (2007).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Has evidence-based medicine ever been modern? A Latour-inspired understanding of a changing EBM</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/evidence-based-medicine-ever-modern-latour-inspired-understanding-changing-ebm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 12:22:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/evidence-based-medicine-ever-modern-latour-inspired-understanding-changing-ebm/</guid>
      <description>Wieringa S, Engebretsen E, Heggen K, Greenhalgh T. Journal of Evaluation in Clinical Practice, 2017 Abstract Evidence-based health care (EBHC), previously evidence-based medicine (EBM), is considered by many to have modernized health care and brought it from an authority-based past to a more rationalist, scientific grounding. But recent concerns and criticisms pose serious challenges and urge us to look at the fundamentals of a changing EBHC. In this paper, we present French philosopher Bruno Latour&#39;s vision on modernity as a framework to discuss current changes in the discourse on EBHC/EBM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s on in Manchester</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/whats-on-in-manchester/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 10:25:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/whats-on-in-manchester/</guid>
      <description>Genealogies of Knowledge I: Translating Political and Scientific Thought across Time and Space 7-9 December 2017 | The University of Manchester
CONFERENCE THEME ABSTRACTS PRESENTERS KEYNOTE SPEAKERS PANELS VENUE REGISTRATION ACCOMMODATION WHAT&#39;S ON IN MANCHESTER PROGRAMME&amp;nbsp;RECORDINGS
Tweet #GoKConf2017
  For more visitor information, including what to do in Manchester, check the TimeOut Manchester and What’s on in Manchester pages.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Henry Jones</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/henry-jones/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 12:30:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/henry-jones/</guid>
      <description>I am the second Post-Doctoral Research Associate to start work on the Genealogies of Knowledge project. Having received my BA in French Studies from the University of Sheffield, I came to Manchester in 2012 as a student enrolled on the MA in Translation and Interpreting Studies programme. During this course, I developed an interest in recent research on web-based communities of non-professional translators, as well as in socio-narrative theory as a conceptual framework for the study of translation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Humanities: Knowledge and Critique in a Digital Age</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/digital-humanities-knowledge-critique-digital-age/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2017 14:56:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/digital-humanities-knowledge-critique-digital-age/</guid>
      <description>David M. Berry, Anders Fagerjord As the twenty-first century unfolds, computers challenge the way in which we think about culture, society and what it is to be human: areas traditionally explored by the humanities. In a world of automation, Big Data, algorithms, Google searches, digital archives, real-time streams and social networks, our use of culture has been changing dramatically. The digital humanities give us powerful theories, methods and tools for exploring new ways of being in a digital age.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Producing inequality: Creative economies in Cairo</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/producing-inequality-creative-economies-cairo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2017 11:13:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/producing-inequality-creative-economies-cairo/</guid>
      <description>Ilka Eickhof | Madamasr.com | April 20, 2017 Economic language has seeped deep into the everyday in western Europe, and is being imported into Egypt through funding. &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Since local state and non-state funding is either scarce or limited in scope, a significant part of Cairo’s contemporary culture field — specifically visual art, dance and partly also theater — depends on funding from western European cultural institutions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calls for Panel Papers: Genealogies of Knowledge I</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/call-panel-papers-genealogies-knowledge-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 12:29:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/call-panel-papers-genealogies-knowledge-i/</guid>
      <description>Genealogies of Knowledge I: Translating Political and Scientific Thought across Time and Space The University of Manchester 7-9 December 2017  &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Submission Period for Contributions to Thematic Panels Now Open The period for the submission to the conference thematic panels is now open. Paper proposals for the thematic panels should be submitted directly to panel convenors by 31 May 2017. Full details on the conference panels and their convenors can be found by clicking on the links below:  Lingua Francas of Knowledges The Magic of ‘Classical’ Languages: Script, Sound and Sense in the Translation of Sacred Concepts Translation and Health Humanities: The Role of Translated Personal Narratives in the Co-creation of Medical Knowledge Dissemination, Contestation, and Mediation of Knowledge between Asia and the West Science and Translation as Culturally Embedded Practices Data-driven conceptual history: new methods and approaches  Further Information Genealogies of Knowledge I: Translating Political and Scientific Thought across Time and Space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genealogies of Knowledge I: Translating Political and Scientific Thought across Time and Space</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/genealogies-knowledge-i-translating-political-scientific-thought-across-time-space-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 08:31:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/genealogies-knowledge-i-translating-political-scientific-thought-across-time-space-2/</guid>
      <description>Genealogies of Knowledge I: Translating Political and Scientific Thought across Time and Space The University of Manchester 7-9 December 2017 Update on Genealogies of Knowledge I Conference The selection of abstracts for the Genealogies of Knowledge I conference has now been completed. In addition to the six plenary sessions, the conference will consist of:  Approximately 40 papers to be delivered as individual presentations, as part of the general programme; Approximately 40 papers to be delivered under one of the nine thematic panels that were submitted for the organisers’ consideration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call for Panel Papers: Data-driven conceptual history: new methods and approaches</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/call-panel-papers-data-driven-conceptual-history-new-methods-approaches/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2017 08:36:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/call-panel-papers-data-driven-conceptual-history-new-methods-approaches/</guid>
      <description>Genealogies of Knowledge I Translating Political and Scientific Thought across Time and Space University of Manchester 7-9 December 2017 Data-driven conceptual history: new methods and approaches Convenors: Jaap Verheul, Pim Huijnen (Utrecht University) Call for Panel Papers (Adobe PDF) This panel aims to bring together scholars to present the state-of-the-art in digital conceptual history and to discuss epistemological and methodological questions related to computational approaches to conceptual change. The digitisation of historical material and the implementation of new computational tools have spurred the study of semantic and conceptual change.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Translation in Science – Science in Translation - International Conference, Giessen, Germany, 30-31 March 2017</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/translation-science-science-translation-international-conference-giessen-germany-30-31-march-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 13:49:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/translation-science-science-translation-international-conference-giessen-germany-30-31-march-2017/</guid>
      <description>14-16 June 2017 International Graduate Centre for the Study of Culture, Justus Liebig University Giessen In recent years, considerable scholarly attention has been drawn to interdisciplinary research between the fields of Translation Studies and History of Science, which has shed light on, for instance, the workings of scientific communities, the dissemination of knowledge across languages and cultures, and the transformation in the process of that knowledge and of the scientific communities involved.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call for Papers: Collection and Fragmentation: Medical Compilations from the Orient and Occident and their Sources</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/call-papers-collection-fragmentation-medical-compilations-orient-occident-sources/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2017 11:50:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/call-papers-collection-fragmentation-medical-compilations-orient-occident-sources/</guid>
      <description>Deadline - 25 May 2017 Charité Universitätsmedizin Berlin From the early Byzantine period, a fundamental change in scientific writing is apparent: Instead of argument-based discursive writing, compilations from older treatises viewed as exemplary are found, compilations that have “encyclopaedic” and paedagogic rather than scientific aims. The most comprehensive writings of this genre are the thematically arranged collections of excerpts (&#34;encyclopaedias&#34;) compiled by Oribasius, Aetius and Paul of Aegina (4th-7th century AD).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Final Call for Papers: Genealogies of Knowledge I</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/final-call-papers-genealogies-knowledge-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 15:18:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/final-call-papers-genealogies-knowledge-i/</guid>
      <description>Genealogies of Knowledge I: Translating Political and Scientific Thought across Time and Space The University of Manchester 7-9 December 2017 Final Call for Papers Hosted by the research team leading the AHRC-funded Genealogies of Knowledge project at the University of Manchester, this conference will provide a forum for engaging with questions of current import in relation to the role of translation in the production and circulation of political, scientific and other key concepts in social life across time and space… » Read more Conference News  Deadline for the submission of individual paper abstracts extended to 31 March by popular demand; Submission period for contributions to thematic panels now open; Full information on keynote speakers and their papers now available online.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call for Papers:  Economies of Cultural Knowledge / London Conference in Critical Thought 2017</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/call-papers-economies-cultural-knowledge-london-conference-critical-thought-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2017 10:27:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/call-papers-economies-cultural-knowledge-london-conference-critical-thought-2017/</guid>
      <description>30 June and 1 July 2017 London South Bank University Neo-liberal capitalism has asserted the primacy of “knowledge” in the cultural sphere. Its “Knowledge Economy” agenda has renewed the dialectics of reason and faith, autonomy and control, progress and tradition. “Creative Industries”, with their attendant emphasis on innovation, information and intellectual property, loom large in this renewal – as do accelerating market and managerial logics in the structures of education and governance that feed the broader “Cultural Economy”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call for Panel Papers: Science and Translation as Culturally Embedded Practices</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/call-panel-papers-science-translation-culturally-embedded-practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2017 16:03:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/call-panel-papers-science-translation-culturally-embedded-practices/</guid>
      <description>Genealogies of Knowledge I Translating Political and Scientific Thought across Time and Space University of Manchester 7-9 December 2017 Science and Translation as Culturally Embedded Practices Convenor: Maeve Olohan, University of Manchester Call for Panel Papers (Adobe PDF) Through the work of science studies, many scholars have come to understand science as culturally situated knowledge practices. This shift in understanding entailed a move away from thinking about science as the pursuit of universal truths and a debunking of the assumptions that science is unified and value-free.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Languages and Culture in History</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/languages-culture-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2017 10:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/languages-culture-history/</guid>
      <description>The series Languages and Culture in History studies the role foreign languages have played in the creation of the linguistic and cultural heritage of Europe, both western and eastern, and at the individual, community, national or transnational level. At the heart of this series is the historical evolution of linguistic and cultural policies, internal as well as external, and their relationship with linguistic and cultural identities. The series takes an interdisciplinary approach to a variety of historical issues: the diffusion, the supply and the demand for foreign languages, the history of pedagogical practices, the historical relationship between languages in a given cultural context, the public and private use of foreign languages – in short, every way foreign languages intersect with local languages in the cultural realm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call for Panel Papers: Dissemination, Contestation, and Mediation of Knowledge between Asia and the West</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/call-panel-papers-dissemination-contestation-mediation-knowledge-asia-west/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2017 15:20:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/call-panel-papers-dissemination-contestation-mediation-knowledge-asia-west/</guid>
      <description>Genealogies of Knowledge I Translating Political and Scientific Thought across Time and Space University of Manchester 7-9 December 2017 Dissemination, Contestation, and Mediation of Knowledge between Asia and the West Convenors: Kyung Hye Kim, Dang Li, Yifan Zhu (Shanghai Jiao Tong University) Call for Panel Papers (Adobe PDF) The dialogue between the West and the East continues to be decisively shaped by various processes of translation, where imported knowledge interacts with local knowledge in a dynamic cycle in which both are transformed to varying degrees.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call for Panel Papers: Translation and Health Humanities: The Role of Translated Personal Narratives in the Co-creation of Medical Knowledge</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/call-panel-papers-translation-health-humanities-role-translated-personal-narratives-co-creation-medical-knowledge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 13:58:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/call-panel-papers-translation-health-humanities-role-translated-personal-narratives-co-creation-medical-knowledge/</guid>
      <description>Genealogies of Knowledge I Translating Political and Scientific Thought across Time and Space University of Manchester 7-9 December 2017 Translation and Health Humanities: The Role of Translated Personal Narratives in the Co-creation of Medical Knowledge Convenor: Şebnem Susam-Saraeva University of Edinburgh Call for Panel Papers (Adobe PDF) Medicine, as an ‘applied science’, has traditionally enjoyed a particularly authoritative and powerful status within society. But while fast-paced scientific discoveries and technological innovations have improved the health of vast populations worldwide, some sections of society are becoming more and more disillusioned with what they regard as rigid, unholistic or wholesale treatments offered by the medical profession, and turning to alternative approaches to health and well-being.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First International Conference on Historical Medical Discourse (CHIMED-1)</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/first-international-conference-historical-medical-discourse-chimed-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2017 10:23:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/first-international-conference-historical-medical-discourse-chimed-1/</guid>
      <description>14-16 June 2017 University of Milan It is a pleasure to announce that the Department of Foreign Languages and Literatures at the University of Milan will host the First International Conference on Historical Medical Discourse (CHIMED-1). The general interest of the conference concerns medical discourse in historical perspective across disciplinary fields and research areas, such as: historical linguistics; historical lexicology and lexicography; medicine in/and literature; history of science, medicine and medical thought; history and social function of medical institutions; popularization of medical thought; translation of medical texts; medicine and cultural attitudes; medicine and society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Corpus Semiotics: Reassessing Context</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/corpus-semiotics-reassessing-context/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2017 14:36:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/corpus-semiotics-reassessing-context/</guid>
      <description>Corpus Semiotics: Reassessing Context Conference Room (C1. 18), Ellen Wilkinson Building, The University of Manchester 5 June 2017 In association with DH@Manchester Keynote Speaker: Professor Svenja Adolphs (University of Nottingham) Corpus analysis, in the tradition of Firth, Halliday and Sinclair, proceeds from the assumption that meaning arises from language in use, rather than language as an abstract system of relations, and hence that context is central to the interpretation of patterns revealed through the use of various tools of corpus analysis, especially concordancing software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Second Call for Papers: Genealogies of Knowledge I</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/second-call-papers-genealogies-knowledge-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2017 13:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/second-call-papers-genealogies-knowledge-i/</guid>
      <description>Genealogies of Knowledge I: Translating Political and Scientific Thought across Time and Space The University of Manchester 7-9 December 2017 Second Call for Papers The production and circulation of knowledge across temporal and cultural spaces is a well-established research theme among classicists and historians of political thought, ideas, science and medicine, but recent developments have opened up new perspectives on this area of study. The study of social knowledge flows has advanced our understanding of these transit processes in critical and productive ways.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kamran Karimullah</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/kamran-karimullah/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2017 14:14:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/kamran-karimullah/</guid>
      <description>I am the first of the Genealogies of Knowledge project’s senior post-doctoral researchers to be appointed. I received my Ph.D. from McGill University in 2014 in Islamic Philosophy. For the past three years I have worked with Peter E. Pormann on Arabic medicine on an ERC-funded project on the Arabic Commentaries on the Hippocratic Aphorisms (2012–2017). I am co-editing with Peter E. Pormann a special issue of Oriens 45.1–2 on the medical commentary tradition in medieval Islam.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call for Panel Papers: Lingua Francas of Knowledge</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/call-panel-papers-lingua-francas-knowledge/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2016 15:30:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/call-panel-papers-lingua-francas-knowledge/</guid>
      <description>Genealogies of Knowledge I Translating Political and Scientific Thought across Time and Space University of Manchester 7-9 December 2017 Lingua Francas of Knowledges Convenor: Karen Bennett Universidade Nova, Lisbon Call for Panel Papers (Adobe PDF) English is today the unrivalled vehicle for the transmission of knowledge, the language in which most scholarship is published, conferences are held, reading is done and lessons taught. However, its rise to prominence is a relatively recent development in the broad sweep of human history.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call for Panel Papers: The Magic of ‘Classical’ Languages Script, Sound and Sense in the Translation of Sacred Concepts</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/call-panel-papers-magic-classical-languages-script-sound-sense-translation-sacred-concepts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2016 14:48:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/call-panel-papers-magic-classical-languages-script-sound-sense-translation-sacred-concepts/</guid>
      <description>Genealogies of Knowledge I Translating Political and Scientific Thought across Time and Space University of Manchester 7-9 December 2017 The Magic of ‘Classical’ Languages Script, Sound and Sense in the Translation of Sacred Concepts Convenor: Hephzibah Israel University of Edinburgh Call for Panel Papers (Adobe PDF) What is the nature of a ‘sacred’ language? When we examine the translation of key concepts and texts across the spectrum of the so-called ‘World Religions’ we find that much of the nature of their transfer or circulation depends on certain conceptions of languages as sign systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call for Papers: The Body Politic: States in the History of Medicine and Health September 2017</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/call-papers-body-politic-states-history-medicine-health-september-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2016 11:49:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/call-papers-body-politic-states-history-medicine-health-september-2017/</guid>
      <description>Biennial Conference of the European Association for the History of Medicine and Health (EAHMH) Carol Davila University of Medicine and Pharmacy, Bucharest 30 August - 2 September 2017 The state, as we have come to know it, is very much a 19th-century creation. After poverty, ill health was the dominant social issue targeted by the interventions of emerging -states. Following the principle of the fair allocation of resources to meet basic social and economic needs, many countries introduced collective funding of health care in the 19th century.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call for Papers: British Society for the History of Science Annual Conference 2017</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/call-papers-british-society-history-science-annual-conference-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2016 10:10:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/call-papers-british-society-history-science-annual-conference-2017/</guid>
      <description>6-9 July 2017 University of York The BSHS Annual Conference will take place from Thursday 6 to Sunday 9 July 2017 at the University of York. The Conferences Committee now invites proposals for individual papers and for sessions from historians of science, technology and medicine, and from their colleagues in the wider scholarly community, on any theme, topic or period. Proposals are welcomed from researchers of all nationalities at all stages of their careers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Associate Position: Genealogies of Knowledge</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/research-associate-position-genealogies-knowledge/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2016 21:51:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/research-associate-position-genealogies-knowledge/</guid>
      <description>VACANCY REF: HUM-09286 Apply here: https://www.jobs.manchester.ac.uk/displayjob.aspx?jobid=12614 Application Deadline: Midnight 15 December 2016  Enquiries about the vacancy, shortlisting and interviews:  Professor Mona Baker (mona.baker@manchester.ac.uk) Professor Luis Pérez-González (luis.perez-gonzalez@manchester.ac.uk) Professor Peter E Pormann (peter.pormann@manchester.ac.uk)  General enquiries: hrservices@manchester.ac.uk Tel: +44 (0)161 275 4499 Technical support: universityofmanchester@helpmeapply.co.uk This vacancy will close for applications at midnight on 15 December 2016. slation Studies BACKGROUND The University of Manchester is the largest single-site university in the UK.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genealogies of Knowledge I: Translating Political and Scientific Thought across Time and Space</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/genealogies-knowledge-i-translating-political-scientific-thought-across-time-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2016 15:58:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/genealogies-knowledge-i-translating-political-scientific-thought-across-time-space/</guid>
      <description>7-9 December 2017 1st Call for Papers &amp;nbsp; The production and circulation of knowledge across temporal and cultural spaces is a well-established research theme among classicists and historians of political thought, ideas, science and medicine, but recent developments have opened up new perspectives on this area of study. The study of social knowledge flows has advanced our understanding of these transit processes in critical and productive ways. While earlier ‘diffusionist’ models of knowledge production and distribution were predicated on the ascendancy of European thought and science, and the treatment of other cultures as no more than producers of data to be collected, theorised and understood, emerging models of social knowledge foreground how the very process of circulation produces new knowledge and recognise the contribution of all actors and locations traversed by such flows over time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tracing the Impact of Latin Translations of Arabic Texts on European Society</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/tracing-impact-latin-translations-arabic-texts-european-society/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2016 10:19:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/tracing-impact-latin-translations-arabic-texts-european-society/</guid>
      <description>In this article, Professor Charles Burnett, a world expert in the history of Islamic influences in Europe at The Warburg Institute (London University), retraces the impact the Latin translations of Arabic texts of science and philosophy had on the intellectual progress of Europe in the decisive period that preceded and prepared the Renaissance. The article is based on an interview conducted with him in 2004. Imagine a period in history, a time when Arab and Islamic cultures were at their zenith, renowned for their learning and scholarship.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jan Buts</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/jan-buts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2016 14:19:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/jan-buts/</guid>
      <description>I am happy to introduce myself as the Genealogies of Knowledge project’s new Ph.D. Student. At my alma mater, KU Leuven, I was trained as a linguist and literary scholar, specialising in the Dutch and English languages. During my early educational years, I developed a keen interest in poetry and rhetorical narratology, research fields which I tended to approach through the lens of contemporary philosophy. After obtaining my Master’s degree in Western Literature, I worked as a research assistant for the Leuven-based MDRN research lab, where I was exposed to the literary production of the modernist period.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conference Announcement 2017</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/conference-announcement-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2016 13:48:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/conference-announcement-2017/</guid>
      <description>Plans for holding the first international conference organized by the Genealogies of Knowledge team are well under way. The conference is intended to provide a space for scholars from diverse disciplinary backgrounds to discuss various aspects of the impact of translation and other processes of mediation on the evolution of concepts across time and space. It will also provide an opportunity for engaging with current discourses that contest the foundations of political and scientific life, with methodological and theoretical issues relating to the use of large electronic corpora for tracing the evolution and contestation of concepts, and with the role of historical and modern lingua francas in constructing knowledge(s) across the full spectrum of human experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arabic translators did far more than just preserve Greek philosophy</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/arabic-translators-far-just-preserve-greek-philosophy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2016 11:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/arabic-translators-far-just-preserve-greek-philosophy/</guid>
      <description>Peter Adamson (Professor of philosophy at the Ludwig Maximilian University of Munich) In European antiquity, philosophers largely wrote in Greek. Even after the Roman conquest of the Mediterranean and the demise of paganism, philosophy was strongly associated with Hellenic culture. The leading thinkers of the Roman world, such as Cicero and Seneca, were steeped in Greek literature; Cicero even went to Athens to pay homage to the home of his philosophical heroes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emerging Democracies Postdoctoral Fellowship</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/emerging-democracies-postdoctoral-fellowship/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2016 09:45:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/emerging-democracies-postdoctoral-fellowship/</guid>
      <description>Fellowship period: September 2017 – May 2018 Application deadline: January 15, 2017 The Weiser Center for Emerging Democracies (WCED) at the University of Michigan invites postdoctoral scholars to apply for the Emerging Democracies Postdoctoral Fellowship. The fellowship supports research on the broad historical, political, economic, and societal conditions under which democracies emerge—and autocracies endure. Three awards are available in 2017-18. Emerging Democracies Postdoctoral Fellows are expected to focus on their own research, participate in WCED workshops and events, and present one public lecture during their fellowship year, while in residence at the University of Michigan, Ann Arbor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Tenth Annual Intensive Introduction to Islamic Codicology</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/tenth-annual-intensive-introduction-islamic-codicology/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2016 10:46:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/tenth-annual-intensive-introduction-islamic-codicology/</guid>
      <description>3–7 October 2016 Cambridge University Library, Cambridge, UK The Islamic Manuscript Association, together with the Thesaurus Islamicus Foundation, Cambridge University Library, and the University of Cambridge&#39;s HRH Prince Alwaleed Bin Talal Centre of Islamic Studies, announces its Tenth Annual Intensive Introduction to Islamic Codicology Course, which will be held from 3-7 October 2016 at the Cambridge University Library. This intensive five-day course will introduce the study of Islamic manuscript codices as physical objects, or the archaeology of the Islamic book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Translation and Knowledge: From Knowledge Production to Collective Intelligence on the Web</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/translation-knowledge-knowledge-production-collective-intelligence-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2016 08:58:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/translation-knowledge-knowledge-production-collective-intelligence-web/</guid>
      <description>12-14 January 2017 Ajou University, South Korea Knowledge production and dissemination have long been of interest to scholars from various disciplinary backgrounds. Within the field of translation studies, the role of translation in the production, transmission and transformation of knowledge has been the focus of recent investigations by a number of research groups, including, but not limited to, the organizers of the Circulation of Academic Thought Conference held in the University of Graz in 2015 and the research team based at the University of Manchester undertaking the UK’s AHRC-funded‘Genealogies of Knowledge Research Project 2016.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Corpus Linguistics Conference 2017</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/corpus-linguistics-conference-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2016 14:26:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/corpus-linguistics-conference-2017/</guid>
      <description>24 - 28 July 2017 University of Birmingham The International Corpus Linguistics Conference 2017 will take place from Monday 24 to Friday 28 July at the University of Birmingham. Opening plenary  Susan Hunston, University of Birmingham  Keynote speakers  Susan Conrad (Portland State University, US) Andrew Hardie (Lancaster University, UK) Christian Mair (University of Freiburg, Germany) Dan McIntyre (University of Huddersfield, UK) Mike Scott (Aston University, UK)  Further Information Further details will be available on this page from autumn 2016 - when the first call for papers will go out: http://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alexander’s Gate and the Unclean Nations: Translation, Textual Appropriation, and the Construction of Barriers</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/alexanders-gate-unclean-nations-translation-textual-appropriation-construction-barriers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2016 15:28:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/alexanders-gate-unclean-nations-translation-textual-appropriation-construction-barriers/</guid>
      <description>Benjamin Garstad  TranscUlturAl, A Journal of Translation and Cultural Studies, 8, 1, 2016 Abstract The Alexander Romance and the Apocalypse of Pseudo-Methodius deserve a place in any discussion of the impact of the translator’s work on the construction of memory in multicultural societies. Both works are remarkable as the products and the objects of translation throughout the middle ages. Successive recensions of the Alexander Romance were translated, either from the original Greek or from Latin translations, into numerous vernacular languages until there were popular versions of the Romance in circulation from Iceland to Indonesia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Body in Translation - Translation, the Human body and Early Modern Demarcations of Knowledge</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/body-translation-translation-human-body-early-modern-demarcations-knowledge/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2016 10:02:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/body-translation-translation-human-body-early-modern-demarcations-knowledge/</guid>
      <description>This project examines how different kinds of human bodies were constituted through translation in medical, ethnographic and religious discourses in the early modern global world. The project aims to historicize present notions of translation by analysing a test case at the interstices of nature and culture. It examines how different kinds of human bodies were constituted through translation in medical, ethnographic and religious discourses in the early modern global world. It is concerned with conceptual and physical dimensions of the human body, and how these intersect with translation as a practice and a concept.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digitizing Early Arabic Printed Books</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/digitizing-early-arabic-printed-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2016 09:51:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/digitizing-early-arabic-printed-books/</guid>
      <description>21 October 2016 Joukowsky Forum, Watson Institute, Brown University The Digital Islamic Humanities Project, a signature initiative of Middle East Studies at Brown University, is pleased to announce its annual scholarly gathering, a workshop on the topic of print culture in the early modern and modern Middle East. The event is organized in partnership with Gale Publishers, which will present its new digital text archive entitled Early Arabic Printed Books from the British Library.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search and visualisation software tools</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/search-visualisation-software-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2016 13:37:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/search-visualisation-software-tools/</guid>
      <description>The Genealogies of Knowledge Corpus is supported by a set of powerful search and visualisation software tools that are being developed specifically for this project. Working with this software will allow the research team to trace the development and mutation of key concepts that have become a core part of our academic and public life, and their contestation and renegotiation by civil society today. Further technical information, examples and documentation are now available on the project website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eleventh Islamic Manuscript Conference: Sufism and Islamic Manuscript Culture</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/eleventh-islamic-manuscript-conference-sufism-islamic-manuscript-culture/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2016 08:32:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/eleventh-islamic-manuscript-conference-sufism-islamic-manuscript-culture/</guid>
      <description>13–15 September 2016 Magdalene College, University of Cambridge The Islamic Manuscript Association, in partnership with the Thesaurus Islamicus Foundation and the HRH Prince Alwaleed Bin Talal Centre of Islamic Studies at the University of Cambridge, is pleased to announce its Eleventh Islamic Manuscript Conference: Sufism and Islamic Manuscript Culture, which will be held from 13 to 15 September 2016 at Magdalene College, University of Cambridge, United Kingdom. Sufis have written litanies, panegyrics, didactic works in verse and prose, hagiographies, discourses, exegetical works, and metaphysical treatises made into manuscripts both humble and lavish.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Culture and politics of data visualisation: A one-day conference</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/culture-politics-data-visualisation-one-day-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2016 09:32:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/culture-politics-data-visualisation-one-day-conference/</guid>
      <description>10 October 2016 The University of Sheffield As data become more and more abundant, the main way that most people get access to them is through their visualisation. To date, much academic research about data visualisation has focused on individualistic and micro-level factors like memorability and speed of comprehension and has not attended to the social, cultural, political work that visualisations do, the contexts in which they circulate, and the mutually constitutive relationships between visualisations and their contexts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The construction of medieval Arab medicine</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/construction-medieval-arab-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2016 14:07:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/construction-medieval-arab-medicine/</guid>
      <description>The construction of medieval Arab medicine Edited by Pauline Koetschet and Peter E. Pormann (2016, Institut français du Proche-Orient) The history of pre-modern Arabic medicine remains shrouded in mystery, not because we would not have sources, but because in their majority, these sources have not been edited or studied. These are the sources that form the basis of the articles published in this book. These deal, inter alia, the transfer of medical knowledge and the construction of the Arab medicine from Greek sources, Indian, Persian and translated into Arabic, and the changes made to past medical knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Citizen Media and Public Spaces</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/citizen-media-public-spaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2016 10:57:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/citizen-media-public-spaces/</guid>
      <description>Citizen Media and Public Spaces  Diverse Expressions of Citizenship and Dissent Edited by Mona Baker and Bolette B. Blaagaard (2016, Routledge) Citizen Media and Public Spaces presents a pioneering exploration of citizen media as a highly interdisciplinary domain that raises vital political, social and ethical issues relating to conceptions of citizenship and state boundaries, the construction of publics and social imaginaries, processes of co-optation and reverse co-optation, power and resistance, the ethics of witnessing and solidarity, and novel responses to the democratic deficit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linnaeus&#39; Restless System: Translation as Textual Engineering in Eighteenth-Century Botany</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/linnaeus-restless-system-translation-textual-engineering-eighteenth-century-botany/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2016 10:35:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/linnaeus-restless-system-translation-textual-engineering-eighteenth-century-botany/</guid>
      <description>Bettina Dietza Annals of Science, 2015 Summary This article discusses translations of Linnaeus&#39; Systema naturae into various European languages, in the context of successively expanded editions of Linnaeus&#39; writings. The ambition and intention of most translators was not only to make the Systema naturae accessible for practical botanical use by a wider readership, but also to supplement and correct it, and thus to shape it. This form of textual engineering, becoming increasingly complex with each translation cycle, shaped the external appearance of new editions of the Systema, and reflected the modular architecture of a botanical system designed for expansion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Undone Science: Charting Social Movement and Civil Society Challenges to Research Agenda Setting</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/undone-science-charting-social-movement-civil-society-challenges-research-agenda-setting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2016 14:52:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/undone-science-charting-social-movement-civil-society-challenges-research-agenda-setting/</guid>
      <description>Scott Frickel, Sahra Gibbon, Jeff Howard,Joanna Kempner, Gwen Ottinger, and David J. Hess Science, Technology, &amp;amp; Human Values 35(4), July 2010 Summary &#39;Undone science&#39; is a term used to describe areas of research that are left unfunded, incomplete, or generally ignored but which social movements or civil society organizations often identify as worthy of more research. This article draws on recent studies to elaborate the concept of undone science as it relates to the political construction of research agendas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magna Carta – 800 years on</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/magna-carta-800-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2016 13:49:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/magna-carta-800-years/</guid>
      <description>The Guardian&amp;nbsp;featured an article on theeight hundredth anniversary of Magna Carta in 2015 and the publication David Carpenter’s new translation of Magna Carta as a Penguin Classic, discussing scholarly work on the Magna Carta and its perceived and disputed historical and contemporary legacies.
 Magna Carta (Penguin Classics, David Carpenter, 2015)
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The letter, the dictionary and the laboratory: translating chemistry and mineralogy in eighteenth-century France</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/letter-dictionary-laboratory-translating-chemistry-mineralogy-eighteenth-century-france/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2016 15:34:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/letter-dictionary-laboratory-translating-chemistry-mineralogy-eighteenth-century-france/</guid>
      <description>Patrice Bret Annals of Science, 2015 Summary Eighteenth-century scientific translation was not just a linguistic or intellectual affair. It included numerous material aspects requiring a social organization to marshal the indispensable human and non-human actors. Paratexts and actors&#39; correspondences provide a good observatory to get information about aspects such as shipments and routes, processes of translation and language acquisition (dictionaries, grammars and other helpful materials, such as translated works in both languages), texts acquisition and dissemination (including author&#39;s additions and corrections, oral presentations in academic meetings and announcements of forthcoming translations).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Human Rights, Society and Multi-Level Governance Scholarship</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/human-rights-society-multi-level-governance-scholarship/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2016 10:06:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/human-rights-society-multi-level-governance-scholarship/</guid>
      <description>Western Sydney University has advertised a joint Ph. D. program coordinated by the University of Padova in Italy. The aim of the program is to develop researchers with a multi/interdisciplinary profile. The program includes research and training in the area of human rights studies, covering the various legal, social, philosophical and economic approaches and methodologies and different geographical areas. The successful candidate will be based at Western Sydney University, and will have the opportunity to study for at least one semester in Croatia, Greece or Italy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing Human Rights and Getting It Wrong</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/writing-human-rights-getting-wrong/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2016 10:18:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/writing-human-rights-getting-wrong/</guid>
      <description>Alex de Waal Boston Review: June 06, 2016 http://bostonreview.net/world/alex-de-waal-writing-human-rights The power to accuse someone of a grave crime on the basis of hearsay is a heady one. I have done it, and I faced the consequences of being wrong. Twenty years ago in the Nuba Mountains of central Sudan, I met a man, Chief Hussein Karbus, whose murder I had reported three years earlier. He was introduced to me by the man I had accused of ordering his death, a leader of the Sudan People’s Liberation Army.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Corpus Linguistics: Method, Analysis, Interpretation</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/corpus-linguistics-method-analysis-interpretation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2016 08:52:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/corpus-linguistics-method-analysis-interpretation/</guid>
      <description>The Future Learn platform has introduced an online course developed by Lancaster University. The course offers a practical introduction to the methodology of corpus linguistics for researchers in social sciences and humanities. The course aims to:  Equip those taking the course with skills necessary for collecting and analysing large digital collections of text (corpora); Provide educational support for those who want to use the corpus method; demonstrate the use of corpus linguistics in the humanities, especially History Give a sense of the incredibly wide uses that corpora have been put to; Allow those with an interest in language, who have not heard of the corpus approach before, a new way of looking at language; Demonstrate that corpus approaches to social science can offer valuable insight into social reality by investigating the use and manipulation of language in society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Translation and Contestation of Political and Scientific Concepts across Time and Space: A Corpus-Based Study</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/translation-contestation-political-scientific-concepts-across-time-space-corpus-based-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2016 14:16:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/translation-contestation-political-scientific-concepts-across-time-space-corpus-based-study/</guid>
      <description>Hong Kong Baptist University Library - Scholarly Talks Centre for Translation (18 February, 2016) &amp;nbsp;
 [siteorigin_widget class=&#34;WP_Widget_Media_Image&#34;][/siteorigin_widget]The Translation and Contestation of Political and Scientific Concepts across Time and Space: A Corpus-Based Study (Prof. Mona Baker)
This seminar introduced a large, interdisciplinary research project based at the University of Manchester in the UK and funded by the Arts and Humanities Research Council. The project involves compiling large electronic corpora of ancient Greek, medieval Arabic, Latin and Modern English to examine how central concepts in the humanities and sciences have been (re)translated into these three lingua francas, and how they have been interpreted and reinterpreted as they entered new cultural and temporal spaces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call for Papers: ARTIS@Manchester2016</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/call-papers-artismanchester2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2016 09:42:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/call-papers-artismanchester2016/</guid>
      <description>Materiality, Digital Cultures and Transmission in Translation Studies Graduate School, Ellen Wilkinson Building, University of Manchester 11-12 November 2016 Organised by @ctismanchester and @ARTISinitiative https://artisinitiative.org/events/artismanchester2016 Keynote Speakers: Dr Guyda Armstrong (University of Manchester) Dr Serenella Zanotti (University of Rome) This two-day event focuses on material and digital cultures, and textual transmission, promoting conversations about how we conceptualise, encounter and research materials and materiality in translation studies. The event provides a space for exploring concepts of materiality in relation to invention, circulation, performance and interpretation, and considers questions such as:  how do current understandings of materiality in translation studies shape our approach to research design?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Congratulations to Luis Pérez-González</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/congratulations-luis-perez-gonzalez/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2016 17:09:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/congratulations-luis-perez-gonzalez/</guid>
      <description>&amp;nbsp; The Genealogies of Knowledge team is pleased to announce that one of its key members, Co-Investigator Luis Pérez-González, has been promoted to a Chair in Translation Studies at the University of Manchester, in recognition of his achievements in the field. Professor Pérez-González is a translation studies scholar with extensive experience in corpus-driven research and the study of citizen media and activism in the digital culture. He is leading the second strand of analysis on the Genealogies of Knowledge project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Civil Society as Ideology in the Middle East: A Critical Perspective</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/civil-society-ideology-middle-east-critical-perspective/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2016 10:28:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/civil-society-ideology-middle-east-critical-perspective/</guid>
      <description>Jessica Leigh Doyle British Journal of Middle Eastern Studies Volume 43, Issue 3, 2016 Since the early 1990s support for civil society has constituted the linchpin of international efforts in the Middle East North Africa (MENA) to promote democratisation and democratic values.The rationale for this support lies in an understanding of civil society drawn from a liberal-democratic model, which dominates debates about civil society. This article highlights the inaccuracies of this model when applied to the MENA and, using Turkey as an example, draws attention to the perils of supporting civil society organisations (CSOs) based on its conjectures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Translating &#39;Nation&#39; into Japanese during the Modernization of Japan: Dynamics of Translation as a Social and Interactional Practice</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/translating-nation-japanese-modernization-japan-dynamics-translation-social-interactional-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 14:27:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/translating-nation-japanese-modernization-japan-dynamics-translation-social-interactional-practice/</guid>
      <description>Mino Saito (Juntendo University, Tokyo, Japan) and Mutsuko Tsuboi (Rikkyo University, Tokyo, Japan) Meta: Journal des traducteurs / Meta: Translators’ Journal Volume 60, numéro 2, août 2015, p. 369 This article focuses on the translation of the term &#39;nation&#39; into Japanese during the Meiji period (1868-1912). It explores the dynamics of translation practice as an interaction occurring in sociocultural and historical contexts. The discussion revisits the roles played by translation in the modernization of Japan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From an Empire to a Nation State: Importing the Concept of Nation into Ottoman/Turkish Thinking</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/empire-nation-state-importing-concept-nation-ottomanturkish-thinking/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 09:53:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/empire-nation-state-importing-concept-nation-ottomanturkish-thinking/</guid>
      <description>Elif Daldeniz (Okan University, Istanbul, Turkey) Meta: Journal des traducteurs / Meta: Translators’ Journal Volume 59, numéro 1, avril 2014, p. 72-96 This article presents preliminary research results on the role of translation in the introduction of the concept of nation into the Ottoman/Turkish culture. This study, which is linked to a study on the concept of ‘culture’, was based on an interdisciplinary approach relying on the perspectives and notions of translation studies and on methodology developed in conceptual history.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arabic and Latin Glossary</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/arabic-latin-glossary/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2016 08:48:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/arabic-latin-glossary/</guid>
      <description>The Arabic and Latin Glossary is a dictionary of the vocabulary of the Arabic–Latin translations of the Middle Ages. It unites the entries of all existing Arabic–Latin glossaries in modern editions of medieval works. The Glossary has a double aim: to improve our understanding of the Arabic influence in Europe, especially with respect to scientific vocabulary, and to provide a lexical tool for the understanding of Arabic and Latin scientific texts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Translation in Antiquity, Translating Antiquity: Methods and practices</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/translation-antiquity-translating-antiquity-methods-practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2016 10:32:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/translation-antiquity-translating-antiquity-methods-practices/</guid>
      <description>Confirmed keynote speakers: Rachel Mairs, University of Reading; Siobhan McElduff, University of British Columbia; Oliver Taplin, University of Oxford. The thematic area Traveling Texts. Translation and Transnational Reception at the Faculty of Humanities at the University of Oslo is organising a two-day workshop on the broad topic of translations of Greek and Latin texts in antiquity and in modern times. The focus may be on translation as linguistic transfer and/or as cultural reception, and contributors are encouraged to incorporate methodological perspectives even when discussing case-studies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How a thousand years of Arabic scholarship advanced scientific debate</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/thousand-years-arabic-scholarship-advanced-scientific-debate/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2016 09:23:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/thousand-years-arabic-scholarship-advanced-scientific-debate/</guid>
      <description>The Guardian recently featured an article including examples of important manuscripts illustrating how, from the ninth to the nineteenth centuries, scholars and scribes used Arabic as a lingua franca to debate and develop scientific ideas. Arabic-speaking scholars translated classical Greek, Persian and even Sanskrit texts on topics such as medicine, mathematics and astronomy. These scholars went far beyond translation and preservation and fostered a unique and vibrant scientific culture within the Arabic-speaking world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Associate: Genealogies of Knowledge (available from 1 January 2017 to 31 March 2020)</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/research-associate-genealogies-of-knowledge-available-from-1-january-2017-to-31-march-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2016 13:40:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/research-associate-genealogies-of-knowledge-available-from-1-january-2017-to-31-march-2020/</guid>
      <description>University of Manchester Closing date : 29/05/2016 Reference : HUM-08115 Genealogies of Knowledge: The Evolution and Contestation of Concepts across Time and Space is a 4-year, AHRC-funded project investigating the historical evolution and transformation through translation of key concepts in political and scientific thought that can often be traced back to the ancient Greek world, focusing on translations into early medieval Arabic, Latin and modern English. The research involves compiling large electronic corpora of texts and developing software applications to interrogate them and assist with the presentation of findings to other researchers and the public.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Toledo Translation Fund: Call for Donations</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/the-toledo-translation-fund-call-for-donations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2016 18:46:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/the-toledo-translation-fund-call-for-donations/</guid>
      <description>By Rosie Warren / 15 January 2016
The Toledo Translation Fund was established to support the translation into English of major works in the humanities and social sciences, from a wide range of world languages and cultures. Named after the twelfth- and thirteenth-century Toledo School of Translators—whose translations of philosophical and scientific treatises from Arabic, Greek and Hebrew paved the way for the Renaissance—Toledo Translation Fund projects will focus on texts that are sure to be of enduring value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Democracy Emerges from the Spaces In Between</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/democracy-emerges-from-the-spaces-in-between/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2016 20:13:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/democracy-emerges-from-the-spaces-in-between/</guid>
      <description>David Graeber There Never Was a West Or, Democracy Emerges From the Spaces In Between  Part I: On the Incoherence Of the Notion of the “Western Tradition”
Parenthetical Note: On the Slipperiness of the Western Eye
World-Systems Reconfigured
Part II: Democracy Was Not Invented
Part III: On the Emergence of the “Democratic Ideal”
Part IV: Recuperation
The “Influence Debate”
Traditions as Acts of Endless Refoundation
Part V: The Crisis of the State</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Translation and Time</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/translation-and-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2016 20:24:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/translation-and-time/</guid>
      <description>EXPLORING THE TEMPORAL DIMENSION OF CROSS-CULTURAL TRANSFER Department of Translation, The Chinese University of Hong Kong CALL FOR PAPERS / PANELS Largely overshadowed by the metaphor of space, the relation between translation and time/temporality remains surprisingly untheorized and understudied. Except for some isolated references (Cronin 2003; Baker 2006; Bassnett 2013), there has been no sustained engagement with the issue, let alone an attempt to do what Paul Ricoeur has done for narrative theory in his Temps et récit (1983).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Translation and Religion, 1-3 September 2016</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/translation-and-religion-1-3-september-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2016 20:16:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/translation-and-religion-1-3-september-2016/</guid>
      <description>Call for papers: Translation and Religion: Interrogating Concepts, Methods and Practices 1-3 September 2016 University of Edinburgh, 1-3 September 2016 Abstract Submissions Deadline: April 15, 2016 What is the relationship between ‘translation’ and ‘religion’? While all ‘religions’ travel and engage in translation of one kind or another, what gets translated? How do the different components of what is currently understood as ‘religion’—texts, practices, experiences, inner faith or belief systems—translate differently? How can we analyze such commonly held beliefs that some languages simply are sacred and should not be translated?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arabic and Persian Medical Books and Manuscripts</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/arabic-and-persian-medical-books-and-manuscripts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2016 14:57:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/arabic-and-persian-medical-books-and-manuscripts/</guid>
      <description>This digitized collection of selected volumes of medical books and manuscripts, dating from 1300 to 1921, is drawn from theMedical Historical Library, Cushing/Whitney Medical Library. This collection reflects the Arabic and Persian intellectual efforts that translated, augmented, and transmitted Greek and Roman medical knowledge to Western societies during the Renaissance. It includes iconic works by authors such as Avicenna and al-Razi. The Medical Historical Library, originally formed by the joining of three collections by bibliophiles Harvey Cushing, John Fulton, and Arnold Klebs, has over 120,000 volumes dating from the 12th to the 21st centuries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2016 08:56:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/research/</guid>
      <description>Research Team Mona Baker - Selected Publications (For a full list, see http://www.manchester.ac.uk/research/mona.baker/publications) Edited books 2016. (with Bolette Blaagaard) Citizen Media and Public Spaces: Diverse Expressions of Citizenship and Dissent, Abingdon &amp;amp; New York: Routledge. 2016. Translating Dissent: Voices from and with the Egyptian Revolution, Abingdon &amp;amp; New York: Routledge. Winner of the Inttranews 2016 Linguists of the Year Award. http://www.solidarites.org/en/espace-presse/nos-communiques/1344-the-2016-inttranews-linguists-of-the-year-donate-their-prize-money-to-solidarites-international Selected journal articles 2016. &#39;The Prefigurative Politics of Translation in Place-Based Movements of Protest: Subtitling in the Egyptian Revolution&#39;, The Translator 22(1): 1-21.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>