<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>publications on Genealogies</title>
    <link>https://monabaker.org/tags/publications/</link>
    <description>Recent content in publications on Genealogies</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 15:22:57 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://monabaker.org/tags/publications/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Translation and conceptual change: The historical development of jiao 教 in Chinese and its impact on the concept of ‘religion’ in English scholarship</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/translation-and-conceptual-change-the-historical-development-of-jiao-%e6%95%99-in-chinese-and-its-impact-on-the-concept-of-religion-in-english-scholar/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 15:22:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/translation-and-conceptual-change-the-historical-development-of-jiao-%e6%95%99-in-chinese-and-its-impact-on-the-concept-of-religion-in-english-scholar/</guid>
      <description>The historical development of jiao 教 in Chinese and its impact on the concept of ‘religion’ in English scholarship I-Hsin Chen | The Chinese University of Hong Kong Translation and Interpreting Studies, 13(2): 317–336. Link: https://benjamins.com/catalog/tis.13.2   ABSTRACT: This article contends that the traditional Chinese concept of jiao (teaching) has, through translation, greatly influenced the conceptual development of ‘religion’ in English-language scholarship. The article first demonstrates how the historical development of jiao in Chinese reveals numerous previously neglected patterns of Chinese spirituality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Translation and conceptual change: Consequences of the conflation of xiao and filial piety in English</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/translation-and-conceptual-change-consequences-of-the-conflation-of-xiao-and-filial-piety-in-english/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 15:19:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/translation-and-conceptual-change-consequences-of-the-conflation-of-xiao-and-filial-piety-in-english/</guid>
      <description>Consequences of the conflation of xiao and filial piety in English James St. André | The Chinese University of Hong Kong Translation and Interpreting Studies, 13(2): 293–316. Link: https://benjamins.com/catalog/tis.13.2   ABSTRACT: This article examines the development over time of the English expression “filial piety” in order to document how, at least partly in response to pressure from an equivalence that is established with the Chinese term xiao (孝) in the seventeenth century, the term takes on new and increasingly negative connotations in English.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arabographic Optical Character Recognition (OCR)</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/arabographic-optical-character-recognition-ocr/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2017 10:06:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/arabographic-optical-character-recognition-ocr/</guid>
      <description>The OpenITI team, building on the foundational open-source OCR work of Leipzig University’s Alexander von Humboldt Chair for Digital Humanities, has reported Optical Character Recognition (OCR) percentage accuracy rates for classical Arabic-script texts in the high nineties. These numbers are based on tests of seven different Arabic-script texts of varying quality and typefaces, totaling over 7,000 lines (approx. 400 pages, 87,000 words). These accuracy rates not only represent a distinct improvement over the actual accuracy rates of the various proprietary OCR options for classical Arabic-script texts, but, equally important, they are produced using an open-source OCR software called Kraken (developed by Benjamin Kiessling, Leipzig University), that is to be made freely available to the broader Islamic, Persian, and Arabic Studies communities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Translation in the pre-modern world</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/translation-pre-modern-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2017 12:51:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/translation-pre-modern-world/</guid>
      <description>Karla Mallette Middle Eastern Literatures, 2017 Abstract Translation occupies a central place in current theories of world literature, but it is not the only way in which texts circulate beyond their original cultural and temporal contexts to become world literature. This article explores the shifting relationship between language and territory, contrasting modern languages as territorially bound by the nation-state with pre-modern cosmopolitan languages that transcended territorial location. Drawing upon the complex translation process of the works of Aristotle from the Abbasid translation movement of the eighth through 10th centuries to the multiple print editions of competing translations of Aristotle’s works published in Venice in the 16th century, the article argues that world literature often results from the confluence of the broad reach of a cosmopolitan language and the mobility of translation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Has evidence-based medicine ever been modern? A Latour-inspired understanding of a changing EBM</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/evidence-based-medicine-ever-modern-latour-inspired-understanding-changing-ebm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 12:22:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/evidence-based-medicine-ever-modern-latour-inspired-understanding-changing-ebm/</guid>
      <description>Wieringa S, Engebretsen E, Heggen K, Greenhalgh T. Journal of Evaluation in Clinical Practice, 2017 Abstract Evidence-based health care (EBHC), previously evidence-based medicine (EBM), is considered by many to have modernized health care and brought it from an authority-based past to a more rationalist, scientific grounding. But recent concerns and criticisms pose serious challenges and urge us to look at the fundamentals of a changing EBHC. In this paper, we present French philosopher Bruno Latour&#39;s vision on modernity as a framework to discuss current changes in the discourse on EBHC/EBM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Humanities: Knowledge and Critique in a Digital Age</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/digital-humanities-knowledge-critique-digital-age/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2017 14:56:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/digital-humanities-knowledge-critique-digital-age/</guid>
      <description>David M. Berry, Anders Fagerjord As the twenty-first century unfolds, computers challenge the way in which we think about culture, society and what it is to be human: areas traditionally explored by the humanities. In a world of automation, Big Data, algorithms, Google searches, digital archives, real-time streams and social networks, our use of culture has been changing dramatically. The digital humanities give us powerful theories, methods and tools for exploring new ways of being in a digital age.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Producing inequality: Creative economies in Cairo</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/producing-inequality-creative-economies-cairo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2017 11:13:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/producing-inequality-creative-economies-cairo/</guid>
      <description>Ilka Eickhof | Madamasr.com | April 20, 2017 Economic language has seeped deep into the everyday in western Europe, and is being imported into Egypt through funding. &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Since local state and non-state funding is either scarce or limited in scope, a significant part of Cairo’s contemporary culture field — specifically visual art, dance and partly also theater — depends on funding from western European cultural institutions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Languages and Culture in History</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/languages-culture-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2017 10:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/languages-culture-history/</guid>
      <description>The series Languages and Culture in History studies the role foreign languages have played in the creation of the linguistic and cultural heritage of Europe, both western and eastern, and at the individual, community, national or transnational level. At the heart of this series is the historical evolution of linguistic and cultural policies, internal as well as external, and their relationship with linguistic and cultural identities. The series takes an interdisciplinary approach to a variety of historical issues: the diffusion, the supply and the demand for foreign languages, the history of pedagogical practices, the historical relationship between languages in a given cultural context, the public and private use of foreign languages – in short, every way foreign languages intersect with local languages in the cultural realm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tracing the Impact of Latin Translations of Arabic Texts on European Society</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/tracing-impact-latin-translations-arabic-texts-european-society/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2016 10:19:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/tracing-impact-latin-translations-arabic-texts-european-society/</guid>
      <description>In this article, Professor Charles Burnett, a world expert in the history of Islamic influences in Europe at The Warburg Institute (London University), retraces the impact the Latin translations of Arabic texts of science and philosophy had on the intellectual progress of Europe in the decisive period that preceded and prepared the Renaissance. The article is based on an interview conducted with him in 2004. Imagine a period in history, a time when Arab and Islamic cultures were at their zenith, renowned for their learning and scholarship.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arabic translators did far more than just preserve Greek philosophy</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/arabic-translators-far-just-preserve-greek-philosophy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2016 11:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/arabic-translators-far-just-preserve-greek-philosophy/</guid>
      <description>Peter Adamson (Professor of philosophy at the Ludwig Maximilian University of Munich) In European antiquity, philosophers largely wrote in Greek. Even after the Roman conquest of the Mediterranean and the demise of paganism, philosophy was strongly associated with Hellenic culture. The leading thinkers of the Roman world, such as Cicero and Seneca, were steeped in Greek literature; Cicero even went to Athens to pay homage to the home of his philosophical heroes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alexander’s Gate and the Unclean Nations: Translation, Textual Appropriation, and the Construction of Barriers</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/alexanders-gate-unclean-nations-translation-textual-appropriation-construction-barriers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2016 15:28:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/alexanders-gate-unclean-nations-translation-textual-appropriation-construction-barriers/</guid>
      <description>Benjamin Garstad  TranscUlturAl, A Journal of Translation and Cultural Studies, 8, 1, 2016 Abstract The Alexander Romance and the Apocalypse of Pseudo-Methodius deserve a place in any discussion of the impact of the translator’s work on the construction of memory in multicultural societies. Both works are remarkable as the products and the objects of translation throughout the middle ages. Successive recensions of the Alexander Romance were translated, either from the original Greek or from Latin translations, into numerous vernacular languages until there were popular versions of the Romance in circulation from Iceland to Indonesia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The construction of medieval Arab medicine</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/construction-medieval-arab-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2016 14:07:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/construction-medieval-arab-medicine/</guid>
      <description>The construction of medieval Arab medicine Edited by Pauline Koetschet and Peter E. Pormann (2016, Institut français du Proche-Orient) The history of pre-modern Arabic medicine remains shrouded in mystery, not because we would not have sources, but because in their majority, these sources have not been edited or studied. These are the sources that form the basis of the articles published in this book. These deal, inter alia, the transfer of medical knowledge and the construction of the Arab medicine from Greek sources, Indian, Persian and translated into Arabic, and the changes made to past medical knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linnaeus&#39; Restless System: Translation as Textual Engineering in Eighteenth-Century Botany</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/linnaeus-restless-system-translation-textual-engineering-eighteenth-century-botany/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2016 10:35:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/linnaeus-restless-system-translation-textual-engineering-eighteenth-century-botany/</guid>
      <description>Bettina Dietza Annals of Science, 2015 Summary This article discusses translations of Linnaeus&#39; Systema naturae into various European languages, in the context of successively expanded editions of Linnaeus&#39; writings. The ambition and intention of most translators was not only to make the Systema naturae accessible for practical botanical use by a wider readership, but also to supplement and correct it, and thus to shape it. This form of textual engineering, becoming increasingly complex with each translation cycle, shaped the external appearance of new editions of the Systema, and reflected the modular architecture of a botanical system designed for expansion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Undone Science: Charting Social Movement and Civil Society Challenges to Research Agenda Setting</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/undone-science-charting-social-movement-civil-society-challenges-research-agenda-setting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2016 14:52:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/undone-science-charting-social-movement-civil-society-challenges-research-agenda-setting/</guid>
      <description>Scott Frickel, Sahra Gibbon, Jeff Howard,Joanna Kempner, Gwen Ottinger, and David J. Hess Science, Technology, &amp;amp; Human Values 35(4), July 2010 Summary &#39;Undone science&#39; is a term used to describe areas of research that are left unfunded, incomplete, or generally ignored but which social movements or civil society organizations often identify as worthy of more research. This article draws on recent studies to elaborate the concept of undone science as it relates to the political construction of research agendas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magna Carta – 800 years on</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/magna-carta-800-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2016 13:49:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/magna-carta-800-years/</guid>
      <description>The Guardian&amp;nbsp;featured an article on theeight hundredth anniversary of Magna Carta in 2015 and the publication David Carpenter’s new translation of Magna Carta as a Penguin Classic, discussing scholarly work on the Magna Carta and its perceived and disputed historical and contemporary legacies.
 Magna Carta (Penguin Classics, David Carpenter, 2015)
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The letter, the dictionary and the laboratory: translating chemistry and mineralogy in eighteenth-century France</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/letter-dictionary-laboratory-translating-chemistry-mineralogy-eighteenth-century-france/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2016 15:34:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/letter-dictionary-laboratory-translating-chemistry-mineralogy-eighteenth-century-france/</guid>
      <description>Patrice Bret Annals of Science, 2015 Summary Eighteenth-century scientific translation was not just a linguistic or intellectual affair. It included numerous material aspects requiring a social organization to marshal the indispensable human and non-human actors. Paratexts and actors&#39; correspondences provide a good observatory to get information about aspects such as shipments and routes, processes of translation and language acquisition (dictionaries, grammars and other helpful materials, such as translated works in both languages), texts acquisition and dissemination (including author&#39;s additions and corrections, oral presentations in academic meetings and announcements of forthcoming translations).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Civil Society as Ideology in the Middle East: A Critical Perspective</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/civil-society-ideology-middle-east-critical-perspective/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2016 10:28:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/civil-society-ideology-middle-east-critical-perspective/</guid>
      <description>Jessica Leigh Doyle British Journal of Middle Eastern Studies Volume 43, Issue 3, 2016 Since the early 1990s support for civil society has constituted the linchpin of international efforts in the Middle East North Africa (MENA) to promote democratisation and democratic values.The rationale for this support lies in an understanding of civil society drawn from a liberal-democratic model, which dominates debates about civil society. This article highlights the inaccuracies of this model when applied to the MENA and, using Turkey as an example, draws attention to the perils of supporting civil society organisations (CSOs) based on its conjectures.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>