<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>events on Genealogies</title>
    <link>https://monabaker.org/tags/events/</link>
    <description>Recent content in events on Genealogies</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 08:26:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://monabaker.org/tags/events/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Registration now open: Constructing the ‘Public Intellectual’ in the Premodern World</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/registration-now-open-constructing-the-public-intellectual-in-the-premodern-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 08:26:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/registration-now-open-constructing-the-public-intellectual-in-the-premodern-world/</guid>
      <description>Constructing the ‘Public Intellectual’ in the Premodern World A two-day conference co-hosted by the Genealogies of Knowledge project, the Division of Classics, Ancient History and Archaeology, and the Centre for Translation and Intercultural Studies, University of Manchester, UK 5th-6th September 2019 | Chancellors Hotel, Manchester  Call for papers Keynote speakers&amp;nbsp;Important dates
Venue Registration&amp;nbsp;Bursaries Contact
Abstracts
 Registration now open We are pleased to announce that registration for this event is now open.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Edoardo Crisafulli – Demystifying Christian Liberty</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/edoardo-crisafulli-demystifying-christian-liberty/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 15:44:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/edoardo-crisafulli-demystifying-christian-liberty/</guid>
      <description>Demystifying Christian Liberty Edoardo Crisafulli 1 May 2019, 5pm-6.30pm Ellen Wilkinson Building, Room B2.4 University of Manchester  On 1 May 2019, the Genealogies of Knowledge team will be hosting a talk by Dr Edoardo Crisafulli entitled ‘Demystifying Christian Liberty’. No registration is necessary, all are very welcome to attend! &amp;nbsp; Abstract This presentation delves into one of the most hotly debated issues in contemporary political philosophy, and a potential source of conflict in political discourse: the tense and complex relationship between liberalism and Christianity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genealogies of Knowledge II</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/genealogies-of-knowledge-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2019 15:23:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/genealogies-of-knowledge-ii/</guid>
      <description>An international conference hosted by the Centre for Translation and the Translation Programme, Hong Kong Baptist University, Hong Kong
In collaboration with the&amp;nbsp;Genealogies of Knowledge Project, University of Manchester, UK
7-9 April 2020
 CONFERENCE THEME&amp;nbsp;KEYNOTE SPEAKERS VENUE IMPORTANT DATES&amp;nbsp;ABSTRACT / PANEL SUBMISSION
 Conference Theme This conference builds on and extends the theme of Genealogies of Knowledge I, which was held in Manchester in December 2017 and focused on the role of translation in the production and circulation of political, scientific and other key concepts in social life across time and space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CFP: Translation as Political Act</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/cfp-translation-as-political-act/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 16:22:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/cfp-translation-as-political-act/</guid>
      <description>Translation as Political Act Perugia, Italy 9-11 May 2019 A three-day conference hosted by the Dipartimento di Scienze Politiche, University of Perugia, Italy in collaboration with the Genealogies of Knowledge project. Conference website: http://home.translationaspoliticalact.net/ Confirmed speakers include: Mona Baker, Nicole Doerr, Fruela Fernandez, Lynne Franjié, Guy Rooryck and Lieve Jooken.  Call for Papers  Version française Versione italiana  Translation, both in the restricted sense of interlinguistic rewriting and the broader sense of a set of cultural and political activities, has increasingly featured in studies promoting a critical understanding of the development of political ideas and of global history.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Constructing the ‘Public Intellectual’ in the Premodern World</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/4375/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2018 12:53:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/4375/</guid>
      <description>Constructing the &#39;Public Intellectual&#39; in the Premodern World A two-day conference co-hosted by the Genealogies of Knowledge project, the Division of Classics, Ancient History and Archaeology, and the Centre for Translation and Intercultural Studies, University of Manchester, UK
5th-6th September 2019 | Chancellors Hotel, Manchester
 Call for papers Keynote speakers&amp;nbsp;Important dates
Venue Registration&amp;nbsp;Bursaries Contact
Abstracts
 Abstract submission now closed:&amp;nbsp; Please note that the deadline for submitting an abstract for this conference has now passed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Palestinian Animal League (PAL) reports on &#39;Developing and Translating Rights&#39; event</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/the-palestinian-animal-league-pal-reports-on-developing-and-translating-rights-event/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 11:47:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/the-palestinian-animal-league-pal-reports-on-developing-and-translating-rights-event/</guid>
      <description>The blog post reproduced below was written by a member of the Palestinian Animal League (PAL). It reports on the recent Developing and Translating Rights event, hosted by the Genealogies of Knowledge project and held at the University of Manchester on 19th June 2018.  PAL in UK PAL was pleased to be invited to an event organised by the Centre for Translation and Intercultural Studies (https://www.alc.manchester.ac.uk/ctis/) at the University of Manchester (http://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A host of tongues.. Multilingualism, lingua franca and translation in the Early Modern period</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/a-host-of-tongues-multilingualism-lingua-franca-and-translation-in-the-early-modern-period/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2018 14:42:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/a-host-of-tongues-multilingualism-lingua-franca-and-translation-in-the-early-modern-period/</guid>
      <description>Call for Papers 13-15 December 2018 Faculty of Humanities and Social Sciences, Nova University of Lisbon  Conference Website  In the fifteenth and sixteenth centuries, the linguistic situation in Europe was one of remarkable fluidity. Latin, the great scholarly lingua franca of the medieval period, was beginning to crack as the tectonic plates shifted beneath it, but the vernaculars had not yet crystallized into the national languages that they would become a century later, and bi- or multilingualism was still rife.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#39;Developing and Translating Rights&#39; event</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/developing-translating-rights-event/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 09:05:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/developing-translating-rights-event/</guid>
      <description>Developing and Translating Rights A half-day event co-hosted by the Genealogies of Knowledge Project and the Centre for Translation and Intercultural Studies, University of Manchester, UK
19 June 2018 | Ellen Wilkinson Building, University of Manchester
 Programme&amp;nbsp;Abstracts&amp;nbsp;Registration&amp;nbsp;Venue&amp;nbsp;Contact
 About the event The concept of human rights, as enshrined in the UN Declaration of Human Rights, itself translated into more than 501 languages (www.un.org/en), has been gradually expanded to encompass a broad range of specific rights, including civil, cultural, economic, environmental and social rights.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Corpora and Discourse International Conference</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/corpora-discourse-international-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2018 10:49:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/corpora-discourse-international-conference/</guid>
      <description>Call for Papers 22-24 June 2018 Lancaster University The fourth international Corpora and Discourse conference (CAD 2018) will be held at Lancaster University from Friday 22 June to Sunday 24 June 2018. The conference will be hosted by the ESRC Centre for Corpus Approaches to Social Science (CASS). Corpus-Assisted Discourse Studies (CADS) investigates the employment of corpus techniques to examine how language is used in social contexts for communicative purposes. Corpus linguistics is a powerful methodology – a way of using computers to assist the analysis of language so that regularities among many millions of words can be quickly and accurately identified.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>‘Mutations in Citizenship’ event (23 March 2018)</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/registration-now-open-mutations-citizenship-event-23-march-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2017 15:53:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/registration-now-open-mutations-citizenship-event-23-march-2018/</guid>
      <description>‘Mutations in Citizenship’:&amp;nbsp; Activist and translational perspectives on migration and mobility in the age of globalisation A&amp;nbsp;research symposium co-hosted by the Genealogies of Knowledge project and the Centre for Translation and Intercultural Studies, University of Manchester, UK
23&amp;nbsp;March 2018 | Kanaris Theatre, Manchester Museum
 &amp;nbsp; Programme&amp;nbsp;Abstracts&amp;nbsp;Venue&amp;nbsp;Registration&amp;nbsp;Contact  About the event Migration has always played an important role in the history and development of human societies, but the past fifty years have seen marked rises in the movement and mobility of diverse populations worldwide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CFP: Using Corpora in Contrastive and Translation Studies (5th edition)</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/cfp-using-corpora-contrastive-translation-studies-5th-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 16:59:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/cfp-using-corpora-contrastive-translation-studies-5th-edition/</guid>
      <description>&amp;nbsp; The Centre for English Corpus Linguistics of the University of Louvain is organizing the fifth edition of the Using Corpora in Contrastive and Translation Studies conference series in Louvain-la-Neuve (Belgium) on 12-14 September, 2018.  UCCTS is a biennial international conference which was launched by Richard Xiao in 2008 to provide an international forum for the exploration of the theoretical and practical issues pertaining to the creation and use of corpora in contrastive and translation/interpreting studies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Re-Imagining Cultural Histories of The Middle East and North Africa</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/re-imagining-cultural-histories-middle-east-north-africa/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 11:51:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/re-imagining-cultural-histories-middle-east-north-africa/</guid>
      <description>Call for Papers 28 June 2018 SOAS, University of London A conference organised by:  Communication and Media Research Institute, University of Westminster; The Centre for Global Media and Communications, SOAS; Goldsmiths College, University of London; Middle East and North Africa Programme, Chatham House.  To celebrate 10 years of the Middle East Journal of Culture and Communication. Confirmed keynote: Professor Ella Shohat, New York University The Arab uprisings of 2011 have awakened interest in studies of cultural creativity and transformations across different historical epochs in the Middle East and North Africa region.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>‘Mutations in Citizenship’:  Activist and translational perspectives on migration and mobility  in the age of globalisation</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/mutations-citizenship-activist-translational-perspectives-migration-mobility-age-globalisation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 17:42:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/mutations-citizenship-activist-translational-perspectives-migration-mobility-age-globalisation/</guid>
      <description>&amp;nbsp; A research symposium co-hosted by the Genealogies of Knowledge project and the Centre for Translation and Intercultural Studies, University of Manchester, UK 23rd March 2018  Migration has always played an important role in the history and development of human societies, but the past fifty years have seen marked rises in the movement and mobility of diverse populations worldwide. An unprecedented 244 million people now live in a country other than that in which they were born, a figure which has already increased by 41 percent since the start of the new millennium (UN Sustainable Development 2016).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conference Programme: Genealogies of Knowledge I  2017</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/conference-programme-genealogies-knowledge-i-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 10:28:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/conference-programme-genealogies-knowledge-i-2017/</guid>
      <description>Genealogies of Knowledge I: Translating Political and Scientific Thought across Time and Space The University of Manchester 7-9 December 2017 Conference Programme The full programme of the Genealogies of Knowledge 2017 Conference can now be viewed and downloaded from the conference website, in both outline and detailed versions: http://genealogiesofknowledge.net/gok2017conference/programme/ Hosted by the research team leading the AHRC-funded Genealogies of Knowledge project at the University of Manchester, this conference will provide a forum for engaging with questions of current import in relation to the role of translation in the production and circulation of political, scientific and other key concepts in social life across time and space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Governance and Public Health in Early Nineteenth-Century Egypt</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/governance-public-health-early-nineteenth-century-egypt/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2017 09:44:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/governance-public-health-early-nineteenth-century-egypt/</guid>
      <description>Institute for the Study of Muslim Civilisations, London October 19, 2017 Part of DIALOGUES 2017: a thought-provoking series of seminars on governance in Muslim contexts The Governance Programme at the Aga Khan University&#39;s Institute for the Study of Muslim Civilisations is hosting Governance and Public Health in Early Nineteenth-Century Egypt in the fourth seminar of its 2017 Dialogues Series. Dr. Kamran Karimullah will explore the role that medical practice and medical discourse played in the historical evolution of political power and society in nineteenth-century Egypt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Challenge and Promise of Interdisciplinarity</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/challenge-and-promise-of-interdisciplinarity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2017 16:16:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/challenge-and-promise-of-interdisciplinarity/</guid>
      <description>Researching Translation and Interpreting I The Challenge and Promise of Interdisciplinarity 13-15 October 2017 School of Foreign Languages, Shanghai Jiao Tong University, Shanghai, China First Call for Papers A relative newcomer to the academic world and initially associated with vocational training, translation studies is now firmly established as a vibrant research field in many if not most universities around the world. In their various modes and diverse manifestations, translation and interpreting have further engaged scholars located well beyond the boundaries of translation studies – including sociologists, media and film specialists, forensic linguists, literary scholars and political scientists.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ARTIS@COLOGNE 2017</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/artiscologne-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2017 09:47:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/artiscologne-2017/</guid>
      <description>ARTIS Training Event: Corpora in translation and interpreting studies Cologne University of Applied Sciences (TH Köln) 26 October 2017 An ARTIS onsite training event hosted by the Institute of Translation and Multilingual Communication About the event Building on the success of the Translation Research Summer Schools, run by the University of Manchester, the University of Edinburgh and University College London, ARTIS (Advancing Research in Translation and Interpreting Studies) is an international network which supports the training requirements of doctoral students, postdoctoral and early career researchers in translation and interpreting studies, as well as supporting both junior and experienced teaching staff who wish to develop or refresh their research skills.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Democracy, Futurity, and Security in Post-Coup Cairo (Video)</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/democracy-futurity-security-post-coup-cairo-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2017 09:54:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/democracy-futurity-security-post-coup-cairo-video/</guid>
      <description>Dr. Ian Alan Paul (Al-Quds Bard College, Abu Dis, Palestine) is a transdisciplinary artist, theorist, and curator. Drawing upon his fieldwork undertaken between 2013 and 2015, this event at the University of Manchester explored the myriad forms of contestation that emerged between the diverse legacies of the January 2011 uprising and the subsequent 2013 military coup in Cairo, Egypt. The presentation features sections of the online documentary The Conditions of Possibility (2016), reflections on the production of the documentary, and analysis of the competing forms of democratic possibility and suffocating security that continue to unfold in the present.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What was Philology in Arabic?</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/what-was-philology-in-arabic/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2017 10:28:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/what-was-philology-in-arabic/</guid>
      <description>Thursday 13 July - Saturday 15 July 2017 Freie Universität Berlin The international conference will investigate the neglected history of Arabic-Islamic textual practices and interpretative methods in the early modern world from a global and comparative perspective. Although philology has always been a global knowledge practice, no such account of its history has ever been written. Indeed, wherever texts exist, a method of making sense of them has existed as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calls for Panel Papers: Genealogies of Knowledge I</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/call-panel-papers-genealogies-knowledge-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 12:29:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/call-panel-papers-genealogies-knowledge-i/</guid>
      <description>Genealogies of Knowledge I: Translating Political and Scientific Thought across Time and Space The University of Manchester 7-9 December 2017  &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Submission Period for Contributions to Thematic Panels Now Open The period for the submission to the conference thematic panels is now open. Paper proposals for the thematic panels should be submitted directly to panel convenors by 31 May 2017. Full details on the conference panels and their convenors can be found by clicking on the links below:  Lingua Francas of Knowledges The Magic of ‘Classical’ Languages: Script, Sound and Sense in the Translation of Sacred Concepts Translation and Health Humanities: The Role of Translated Personal Narratives in the Co-creation of Medical Knowledge Dissemination, Contestation, and Mediation of Knowledge between Asia and the West Science and Translation as Culturally Embedded Practices Data-driven conceptual history: new methods and approaches  Further Information Genealogies of Knowledge I: Translating Political and Scientific Thought across Time and Space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genealogies of Knowledge I: Translating Political and Scientific Thought across Time and Space</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/genealogies-knowledge-i-translating-political-scientific-thought-across-time-space-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 08:31:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/genealogies-knowledge-i-translating-political-scientific-thought-across-time-space-2/</guid>
      <description>Genealogies of Knowledge I: Translating Political and Scientific Thought across Time and Space The University of Manchester 7-9 December 2017 Update on Genealogies of Knowledge I Conference The selection of abstracts for the Genealogies of Knowledge I conference has now been completed. In addition to the six plenary sessions, the conference will consist of:  Approximately 40 papers to be delivered as individual presentations, as part of the general programme; Approximately 40 papers to be delivered under one of the nine thematic panels that were submitted for the organisers’ consideration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call for Panel Papers: Data-driven conceptual history: new methods and approaches</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/call-panel-papers-data-driven-conceptual-history-new-methods-approaches/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2017 08:36:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/call-panel-papers-data-driven-conceptual-history-new-methods-approaches/</guid>
      <description>Genealogies of Knowledge I Translating Political and Scientific Thought across Time and Space University of Manchester 7-9 December 2017 Data-driven conceptual history: new methods and approaches Convenors: Jaap Verheul, Pim Huijnen (Utrecht University) Call for Panel Papers (Adobe PDF) This panel aims to bring together scholars to present the state-of-the-art in digital conceptual history and to discuss epistemological and methodological questions related to computational approaches to conceptual change. The digitisation of historical material and the implementation of new computational tools have spurred the study of semantic and conceptual change.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Translation in Science – Science in Translation - International Conference, Giessen, Germany, 30-31 March 2017</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/translation-science-science-translation-international-conference-giessen-germany-30-31-march-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 13:49:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/translation-science-science-translation-international-conference-giessen-germany-30-31-march-2017/</guid>
      <description>14-16 June 2017 International Graduate Centre for the Study of Culture, Justus Liebig University Giessen In recent years, considerable scholarly attention has been drawn to interdisciplinary research between the fields of Translation Studies and History of Science, which has shed light on, for instance, the workings of scientific communities, the dissemination of knowledge across languages and cultures, and the transformation in the process of that knowledge and of the scientific communities involved.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call for Papers: Collection and Fragmentation: Medical Compilations from the Orient and Occident and their Sources</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/call-papers-collection-fragmentation-medical-compilations-orient-occident-sources/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2017 11:50:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/call-papers-collection-fragmentation-medical-compilations-orient-occident-sources/</guid>
      <description>Deadline - 25 May 2017 Charité Universitätsmedizin Berlin From the early Byzantine period, a fundamental change in scientific writing is apparent: Instead of argument-based discursive writing, compilations from older treatises viewed as exemplary are found, compilations that have “encyclopaedic” and paedagogic rather than scientific aims. The most comprehensive writings of this genre are the thematically arranged collections of excerpts (&#34;encyclopaedias&#34;) compiled by Oribasius, Aetius and Paul of Aegina (4th-7th century AD).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Final Call for Papers: Genealogies of Knowledge I</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/final-call-papers-genealogies-knowledge-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 15:18:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/final-call-papers-genealogies-knowledge-i/</guid>
      <description>Genealogies of Knowledge I: Translating Political and Scientific Thought across Time and Space The University of Manchester 7-9 December 2017 Final Call for Papers Hosted by the research team leading the AHRC-funded Genealogies of Knowledge project at the University of Manchester, this conference will provide a forum for engaging with questions of current import in relation to the role of translation in the production and circulation of political, scientific and other key concepts in social life across time and space… » Read more Conference News  Deadline for the submission of individual paper abstracts extended to 31 March by popular demand; Submission period for contributions to thematic panels now open; Full information on keynote speakers and their papers now available online.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call for Papers:  Economies of Cultural Knowledge / London Conference in Critical Thought 2017</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/call-papers-economies-cultural-knowledge-london-conference-critical-thought-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2017 10:27:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/call-papers-economies-cultural-knowledge-london-conference-critical-thought-2017/</guid>
      <description>30 June and 1 July 2017 London South Bank University Neo-liberal capitalism has asserted the primacy of “knowledge” in the cultural sphere. Its “Knowledge Economy” agenda has renewed the dialectics of reason and faith, autonomy and control, progress and tradition. “Creative Industries”, with their attendant emphasis on innovation, information and intellectual property, loom large in this renewal – as do accelerating market and managerial logics in the structures of education and governance that feed the broader “Cultural Economy”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call for Panel Papers: Science and Translation as Culturally Embedded Practices</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/call-panel-papers-science-translation-culturally-embedded-practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2017 16:03:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/call-panel-papers-science-translation-culturally-embedded-practices/</guid>
      <description>Genealogies of Knowledge I Translating Political and Scientific Thought across Time and Space University of Manchester 7-9 December 2017 Science and Translation as Culturally Embedded Practices Convenor: Maeve Olohan, University of Manchester Call for Panel Papers (Adobe PDF) Through the work of science studies, many scholars have come to understand science as culturally situated knowledge practices. This shift in understanding entailed a move away from thinking about science as the pursuit of universal truths and a debunking of the assumptions that science is unified and value-free.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call for Panel Papers: Dissemination, Contestation, and Mediation of Knowledge between Asia and the West</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/call-panel-papers-dissemination-contestation-mediation-knowledge-asia-west/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2017 15:20:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/call-panel-papers-dissemination-contestation-mediation-knowledge-asia-west/</guid>
      <description>Genealogies of Knowledge I Translating Political and Scientific Thought across Time and Space University of Manchester 7-9 December 2017 Dissemination, Contestation, and Mediation of Knowledge between Asia and the West Convenors: Kyung Hye Kim, Dang Li, Yifan Zhu (Shanghai Jiao Tong University) Call for Panel Papers (Adobe PDF) The dialogue between the West and the East continues to be decisively shaped by various processes of translation, where imported knowledge interacts with local knowledge in a dynamic cycle in which both are transformed to varying degrees.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call for Panel Papers: Translation and Health Humanities: The Role of Translated Personal Narratives in the Co-creation of Medical Knowledge</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/call-panel-papers-translation-health-humanities-role-translated-personal-narratives-co-creation-medical-knowledge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 13:58:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/call-panel-papers-translation-health-humanities-role-translated-personal-narratives-co-creation-medical-knowledge/</guid>
      <description>Genealogies of Knowledge I Translating Political and Scientific Thought across Time and Space University of Manchester 7-9 December 2017 Translation and Health Humanities: The Role of Translated Personal Narratives in the Co-creation of Medical Knowledge Convenor: Şebnem Susam-Saraeva University of Edinburgh Call for Panel Papers (Adobe PDF) Medicine, as an ‘applied science’, has traditionally enjoyed a particularly authoritative and powerful status within society. But while fast-paced scientific discoveries and technological innovations have improved the health of vast populations worldwide, some sections of society are becoming more and more disillusioned with what they regard as rigid, unholistic or wholesale treatments offered by the medical profession, and turning to alternative approaches to health and well-being.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First International Conference on Historical Medical Discourse (CHIMED-1)</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/first-international-conference-historical-medical-discourse-chimed-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2017 10:23:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/first-international-conference-historical-medical-discourse-chimed-1/</guid>
      <description>14-16 June 2017 University of Milan It is a pleasure to announce that the Department of Foreign Languages and Literatures at the University of Milan will host the First International Conference on Historical Medical Discourse (CHIMED-1). The general interest of the conference concerns medical discourse in historical perspective across disciplinary fields and research areas, such as: historical linguistics; historical lexicology and lexicography; medicine in/and literature; history of science, medicine and medical thought; history and social function of medical institutions; popularization of medical thought; translation of medical texts; medicine and cultural attitudes; medicine and society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Corpus Semiotics: Reassessing Context</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/corpus-semiotics-reassessing-context/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2017 14:36:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/corpus-semiotics-reassessing-context/</guid>
      <description>Corpus Semiotics: Reassessing Context Conference Room (C1. 18), Ellen Wilkinson Building, The University of Manchester 5 June 2017 In association with DH@Manchester Keynote Speaker: Professor Svenja Adolphs (University of Nottingham) Corpus analysis, in the tradition of Firth, Halliday and Sinclair, proceeds from the assumption that meaning arises from language in use, rather than language as an abstract system of relations, and hence that context is central to the interpretation of patterns revealed through the use of various tools of corpus analysis, especially concordancing software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Second Call for Papers: Genealogies of Knowledge I</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/second-call-papers-genealogies-knowledge-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2017 13:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/second-call-papers-genealogies-knowledge-i/</guid>
      <description>Genealogies of Knowledge I: Translating Political and Scientific Thought across Time and Space The University of Manchester 7-9 December 2017 Second Call for Papers The production and circulation of knowledge across temporal and cultural spaces is a well-established research theme among classicists and historians of political thought, ideas, science and medicine, but recent developments have opened up new perspectives on this area of study. The study of social knowledge flows has advanced our understanding of these transit processes in critical and productive ways.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call for Panel Papers: Lingua Francas of Knowledge</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/call-panel-papers-lingua-francas-knowledge/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2016 15:30:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/call-panel-papers-lingua-francas-knowledge/</guid>
      <description>Genealogies of Knowledge I Translating Political and Scientific Thought across Time and Space University of Manchester 7-9 December 2017 Lingua Francas of Knowledges Convenor: Karen Bennett Universidade Nova, Lisbon Call for Panel Papers (Adobe PDF) English is today the unrivalled vehicle for the transmission of knowledge, the language in which most scholarship is published, conferences are held, reading is done and lessons taught. However, its rise to prominence is a relatively recent development in the broad sweep of human history.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call for Panel Papers: The Magic of ‘Classical’ Languages Script, Sound and Sense in the Translation of Sacred Concepts</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/call-panel-papers-magic-classical-languages-script-sound-sense-translation-sacred-concepts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2016 14:48:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/call-panel-papers-magic-classical-languages-script-sound-sense-translation-sacred-concepts/</guid>
      <description>Genealogies of Knowledge I Translating Political and Scientific Thought across Time and Space University of Manchester 7-9 December 2017 The Magic of ‘Classical’ Languages Script, Sound and Sense in the Translation of Sacred Concepts Convenor: Hephzibah Israel University of Edinburgh Call for Panel Papers (Adobe PDF) What is the nature of a ‘sacred’ language? When we examine the translation of key concepts and texts across the spectrum of the so-called ‘World Religions’ we find that much of the nature of their transfer or circulation depends on certain conceptions of languages as sign systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call for Papers: The Body Politic: States in the History of Medicine and Health September 2017</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/call-papers-body-politic-states-history-medicine-health-september-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2016 11:49:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/call-papers-body-politic-states-history-medicine-health-september-2017/</guid>
      <description>Biennial Conference of the European Association for the History of Medicine and Health (EAHMH) Carol Davila University of Medicine and Pharmacy, Bucharest 30 August - 2 September 2017 The state, as we have come to know it, is very much a 19th-century creation. After poverty, ill health was the dominant social issue targeted by the interventions of emerging -states. Following the principle of the fair allocation of resources to meet basic social and economic needs, many countries introduced collective funding of health care in the 19th century.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call for Papers: British Society for the History of Science Annual Conference 2017</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/call-papers-british-society-history-science-annual-conference-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2016 10:10:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/call-papers-british-society-history-science-annual-conference-2017/</guid>
      <description>6-9 July 2017 University of York The BSHS Annual Conference will take place from Thursday 6 to Sunday 9 July 2017 at the University of York. The Conferences Committee now invites proposals for individual papers and for sessions from historians of science, technology and medicine, and from their colleagues in the wider scholarly community, on any theme, topic or period. Proposals are welcomed from researchers of all nationalities at all stages of their careers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genealogies of Knowledge I: Translating Political and Scientific Thought across Time and Space</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/genealogies-knowledge-i-translating-political-scientific-thought-across-time-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2016 15:58:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/genealogies-knowledge-i-translating-political-scientific-thought-across-time-space/</guid>
      <description>7-9 December 2017 1st Call for Papers &amp;nbsp; The production and circulation of knowledge across temporal and cultural spaces is a well-established research theme among classicists and historians of political thought, ideas, science and medicine, but recent developments have opened up new perspectives on this area of study. The study of social knowledge flows has advanced our understanding of these transit processes in critical and productive ways. While earlier ‘diffusionist’ models of knowledge production and distribution were predicated on the ascendancy of European thought and science, and the treatment of other cultures as no more than producers of data to be collected, theorised and understood, emerging models of social knowledge foreground how the very process of circulation produces new knowledge and recognise the contribution of all actors and locations traversed by such flows over time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conference Announcement 2017</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/conference-announcement-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2016 13:48:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/conference-announcement-2017/</guid>
      <description>Plans for holding the first international conference organized by the Genealogies of Knowledge team are well under way. The conference is intended to provide a space for scholars from diverse disciplinary backgrounds to discuss various aspects of the impact of translation and other processes of mediation on the evolution of concepts across time and space. It will also provide an opportunity for engaging with current discourses that contest the foundations of political and scientific life, with methodological and theoretical issues relating to the use of large electronic corpora for tracing the evolution and contestation of concepts, and with the role of historical and modern lingua francas in constructing knowledge(s) across the full spectrum of human experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Translation and Knowledge: From Knowledge Production to Collective Intelligence on the Web</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/translation-knowledge-knowledge-production-collective-intelligence-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2016 08:58:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/translation-knowledge-knowledge-production-collective-intelligence-web/</guid>
      <description>12-14 January 2017 Ajou University, South Korea Knowledge production and dissemination have long been of interest to scholars from various disciplinary backgrounds. Within the field of translation studies, the role of translation in the production, transmission and transformation of knowledge has been the focus of recent investigations by a number of research groups, including, but not limited to, the organizers of the Circulation of Academic Thought Conference held in the University of Graz in 2015 and the research team based at the University of Manchester undertaking the UK’s AHRC-funded‘Genealogies of Knowledge Research Project 2016.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Corpus Linguistics Conference 2017</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/corpus-linguistics-conference-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2016 14:26:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/corpus-linguistics-conference-2017/</guid>
      <description>24 - 28 July 2017 University of Birmingham The International Corpus Linguistics Conference 2017 will take place from Monday 24 to Friday 28 July at the University of Birmingham. Opening plenary  Susan Hunston, University of Birmingham  Keynote speakers  Susan Conrad (Portland State University, US) Andrew Hardie (Lancaster University, UK) Christian Mair (University of Freiburg, Germany) Dan McIntyre (University of Huddersfield, UK) Mike Scott (Aston University, UK)  Further Information Further details will be available on this page from autumn 2016 - when the first call for papers will go out: http://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digitizing Early Arabic Printed Books</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/digitizing-early-arabic-printed-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2016 09:51:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/digitizing-early-arabic-printed-books/</guid>
      <description>21 October 2016 Joukowsky Forum, Watson Institute, Brown University The Digital Islamic Humanities Project, a signature initiative of Middle East Studies at Brown University, is pleased to announce its annual scholarly gathering, a workshop on the topic of print culture in the early modern and modern Middle East. The event is organized in partnership with Gale Publishers, which will present its new digital text archive entitled Early Arabic Printed Books from the British Library.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eleventh Islamic Manuscript Conference: Sufism and Islamic Manuscript Culture</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/eleventh-islamic-manuscript-conference-sufism-islamic-manuscript-culture/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2016 08:32:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/eleventh-islamic-manuscript-conference-sufism-islamic-manuscript-culture/</guid>
      <description>13–15 September 2016 Magdalene College, University of Cambridge The Islamic Manuscript Association, in partnership with the Thesaurus Islamicus Foundation and the HRH Prince Alwaleed Bin Talal Centre of Islamic Studies at the University of Cambridge, is pleased to announce its Eleventh Islamic Manuscript Conference: Sufism and Islamic Manuscript Culture, which will be held from 13 to 15 September 2016 at Magdalene College, University of Cambridge, United Kingdom. Sufis have written litanies, panegyrics, didactic works in verse and prose, hagiographies, discourses, exegetical works, and metaphysical treatises made into manuscripts both humble and lavish.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Culture and politics of data visualisation: A one-day conference</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/culture-politics-data-visualisation-one-day-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2016 09:32:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/culture-politics-data-visualisation-one-day-conference/</guid>
      <description>10 October 2016 The University of Sheffield As data become more and more abundant, the main way that most people get access to them is through their visualisation. To date, much academic research about data visualisation has focused on individualistic and micro-level factors like memorability and speed of comprehension and has not attended to the social, cultural, political work that visualisations do, the contexts in which they circulate, and the mutually constitutive relationships between visualisations and their contexts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call for Papers: ARTIS@Manchester2016</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/call-papers-artismanchester2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2016 09:42:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/call-papers-artismanchester2016/</guid>
      <description>Materiality, Digital Cultures and Transmission in Translation Studies Graduate School, Ellen Wilkinson Building, University of Manchester 11-12 November 2016 Organised by @ctismanchester and @ARTISinitiative https://artisinitiative.org/events/artismanchester2016 Keynote Speakers: Dr Guyda Armstrong (University of Manchester) Dr Serenella Zanotti (University of Rome) This two-day event focuses on material and digital cultures, and textual transmission, promoting conversations about how we conceptualise, encounter and research materials and materiality in translation studies. The event provides a space for exploring concepts of materiality in relation to invention, circulation, performance and interpretation, and considers questions such as:  how do current understandings of materiality in translation studies shape our approach to research design?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Translation in Antiquity, Translating Antiquity: Methods and practices</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/translation-antiquity-translating-antiquity-methods-practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2016 10:32:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/translation-antiquity-translating-antiquity-methods-practices/</guid>
      <description>Confirmed keynote speakers: Rachel Mairs, University of Reading; Siobhan McElduff, University of British Columbia; Oliver Taplin, University of Oxford. The thematic area Traveling Texts. Translation and Transnational Reception at the Faculty of Humanities at the University of Oslo is organising a two-day workshop on the broad topic of translations of Greek and Latin texts in antiquity and in modern times. The focus may be on translation as linguistic transfer and/or as cultural reception, and contributors are encouraged to incorporate methodological perspectives even when discussing case-studies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Translation and Time</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/translation-and-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2016 20:24:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/translation-and-time/</guid>
      <description>EXPLORING THE TEMPORAL DIMENSION OF CROSS-CULTURAL TRANSFER Department of Translation, The Chinese University of Hong Kong CALL FOR PAPERS / PANELS Largely overshadowed by the metaphor of space, the relation between translation and time/temporality remains surprisingly untheorized and understudied. Except for some isolated references (Cronin 2003; Baker 2006; Bassnett 2013), there has been no sustained engagement with the issue, let alone an attempt to do what Paul Ricoeur has done for narrative theory in his Temps et récit (1983).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Translation and Religion, 1-3 September 2016</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/translation-and-religion-1-3-september-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2016 20:16:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/translation-and-religion-1-3-september-2016/</guid>
      <description>Call for papers: Translation and Religion: Interrogating Concepts, Methods and Practices 1-3 September 2016 University of Edinburgh, 1-3 September 2016 Abstract Submissions Deadline: April 15, 2016 What is the relationship between ‘translation’ and ‘religion’? While all ‘religions’ travel and engage in translation of one kind or another, what gets translated? How do the different components of what is currently understood as ‘religion’—texts, practices, experiences, inner faith or belief systems—translate differently? How can we analyze such commonly held beliefs that some languages simply are sacred and should not be translated?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>