<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>feature on Genealogies</title>
    <link>https://monabaker.org/tags/feature/</link>
    <description>Recent content in feature on Genealogies</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 08:26:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://monabaker.org/tags/feature/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Registration now open: Constructing the ‘Public Intellectual’ in the Premodern World</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/registration-now-open-constructing-the-public-intellectual-in-the-premodern-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 08:26:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/registration-now-open-constructing-the-public-intellectual-in-the-premodern-world/</guid>
      <description>Constructing the ‘Public Intellectual’ in the Premodern World A two-day conference co-hosted by the Genealogies of Knowledge project, the Division of Classics, Ancient History and Archaeology, and the Centre for Translation and Intercultural Studies, University of Manchester, UK 5th-6th September 2019 | Chancellors Hotel, Manchester  Call for papers Keynote speakers&amp;nbsp;Important dates
Venue Registration&amp;nbsp;Bursaries Contact
Abstracts
 Registration now open We are pleased to announce that registration for this event is now open.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genealogies of Knowledge II</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/genealogies-of-knowledge-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2019 15:23:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/genealogies-of-knowledge-ii/</guid>
      <description>An international conference hosted by the Centre for Translation and the Translation Programme, Hong Kong Baptist University, Hong Kong
In collaboration with the&amp;nbsp;Genealogies of Knowledge Project, University of Manchester, UK
7-9 April 2020
 CONFERENCE THEME&amp;nbsp;KEYNOTE SPEAKERS VENUE IMPORTANT DATES&amp;nbsp;ABSTRACT / PANEL SUBMISSION
 Conference Theme This conference builds on and extends the theme of Genealogies of Knowledge I, which was held in Manchester in December 2017 and focused on the role of translation in the production and circulation of political, scientific and other key concepts in social life across time and space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genealogies of Knowledge Conference I (Dec. 2017): Video recordings now available</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/genealogies-of-knowledge-conference-i-dec-2017-video-recordings-now-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2018 13:17:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/genealogies-of-knowledge-conference-i-dec-2017-video-recordings-now-available/</guid>
      <description>The Genealogies of Knowledge project team is pleased to announce that video recordings of all six keynote presentations delivered during our first international conference last year in December 2017 are now available to view online. Please click on the links below to access these resources. Each speaker’s abstract and bio data can additionally be found here.  Keynote presentations &amp;nbsp;  Robert Wisnovsky,&#39;Commentaries, Translation and Philosophical Change: The Case of Greek-into-Arabic&#39; Marianne Maeckelbergh, &#39;The Practice of Unknowing: Knowledge Construction and Deconstruction in Social Movement Networks&#39; Eivind Engebretsen,&#39;Knowledge Translation (KT) as Bio-textual Crossings&#39; Edward Baring, ‘What’s Continental about Continental Philosophy?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CFP: Translation as Political Act</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/cfp-translation-as-political-act/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 16:22:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/cfp-translation-as-political-act/</guid>
      <description>Translation as Political Act Perugia, Italy 9-11 May 2019 A three-day conference hosted by the Dipartimento di Scienze Politiche, University of Perugia, Italy in collaboration with the Genealogies of Knowledge project. Conference website: http://home.translationaspoliticalact.net/ Confirmed speakers include: Mona Baker, Nicole Doerr, Fruela Fernandez, Lynne Franjié, Guy Rooryck and Lieve Jooken.  Call for Papers  Version française Versione italiana  Translation, both in the restricted sense of interlinguistic rewriting and the broader sense of a set of cultural and political activities, has increasingly featured in studies promoting a critical understanding of the development of political ideas and of global history.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Constructing the ‘Public Intellectual’ in the Premodern World</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/4375/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2018 12:53:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/4375/</guid>
      <description>Constructing the &#39;Public Intellectual&#39; in the Premodern World A two-day conference co-hosted by the Genealogies of Knowledge project, the Division of Classics, Ancient History and Archaeology, and the Centre for Translation and Intercultural Studies, University of Manchester, UK
5th-6th September 2019 | Chancellors Hotel, Manchester
 Call for papers Keynote speakers&amp;nbsp;Important dates
Venue Registration&amp;nbsp;Bursaries Contact
Abstracts
 Abstract submission now closed:&amp;nbsp; Please note that the deadline for submitting an abstract for this conference has now passed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genealogies of Knowledge Software - Developments and Enhancements</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/genealogies-of-knowledge-software-developments-and-enhancements/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 09:14:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/genealogies-of-knowledge-software-developments-and-enhancements/</guid>
      <description>The Genealogies of Knowledge project has recently announced the release of the GoK corpus browser interface for researchers wishing to work with the range of corpora developed as part of this project. This is a substantial resource which is constantly being expanded. It currently consists of the following sections:  Modern English Corpus: 17,757,212 tokens Internet English Corpus: 1,201,414 tokens Classical Greek Corpus: 2,763,315 tokens Early Latin Corpus: 866,462 tokens Medieval Arabic Corpus: 1,545,223 tokens  New Features New functionalities have also now been added to the main concordancing interface: Once you have generated a concordance, you can now delete a line by clicking on the Delete Line button in the right-hand corner of the screen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Democracy, Futurity, and Security in Post-Coup Cairo (Video)</title>
      <link>https://monabaker.org/post/democracy-futurity-security-post-coup-cairo-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2017 09:54:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monabaker.org/post/democracy-futurity-security-post-coup-cairo-video/</guid>
      <description>Dr. Ian Alan Paul (Al-Quds Bard College, Abu Dis, Palestine) is a transdisciplinary artist, theorist, and curator. Drawing upon his fieldwork undertaken between 2013 and 2015, this event at the University of Manchester explored the myriad forms of contestation that emerged between the diverse legacies of the January 2011 uprising and the subsequent 2013 military coup in Cairo, Egypt. The presentation features sections of the online documentary The Conditions of Possibility (2016), reflections on the production of the documentary, and analysis of the competing forms of democratic possibility and suffocating security that continue to unfold in the present.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>